<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.1.2" created="2013-04-28 22:35" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/"
>

<channel>
	<title>The College Hill Independent</title>
	<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent</link>
	<description></description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 22:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.1</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>admin</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>theindy@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>oldindy</wp:author_login><wp:author_email></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[oldindy]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>3</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>indysports</wp:author_login><wp:author_email></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[indysports]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>4</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>XMLimports</wp:author_login><wp:author_email></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[XMLimports]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>5</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>indyscience</wp:author_login><wp:author_email></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[indyscience]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>6</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>indystaff</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>theindyads@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[indystaff]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Indy]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Staffer]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.1.2</generator>

	<item>
		<title>Forever on the Edge</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8221</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8221</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/punk2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8224" title="punk" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/punk2-279x300.png" alt="" width="279" height="300" /></a>

by Megan Hauptman

“The last time I played a show, the audience was pornographic with cameras,” Ian MacKaye says, scowling out over the crowd assembled in front of him. “Let’s all put our devices away and try to just be present for this one.” A few audience members sheepishly lower iPhones; one man in front of me tucks a hefty DSLR behind his back, the zoom lens jutting out into the audience like another limb. Most audience members look amused at the request, but not surprised. MacKaye is well known for his cantankerous style.

Ian MacKaye is one half of The Evens; the other half is his wife, Amy Farina. Both are dressed unassumingly in jeans and solid dark t-shirts. MacKaye wears a slouchy black beanie, though he is now almost 51. The two are playing in the charter school’s pale green assembly room. MacKaye is the former frontman of Teen Idles, Minor Threat and Fugazi, famous DC hardcore bands. Farina is the former drummer for DC rock darlings Ted Leo and the Pharmacists. The two married and later formed The Evens, a minimalist duo of drums and guitar backing soft, almost mumbled vocals, and have released three albums together: <em>The Evens</em> (2005), <em>Get Evens</em> (2006), and in November of last year, <em>The Odds</em>.

Home for winter break, a bunch of friends and I are at The Evens’ fundraiser show for the Next Step Public Charter School in Washington, DC. It costs five dollars, which has been the going rate for any MacKaye show since Minor Threat first hit it big. The school, which serves mainly older immigrants trying to get a high school diploma while working, used to be the site of the Wilson Center, a hotbed of punk shows and radical activism in the ’80s. As the show fills with black-clad original punks, I start to feel like I’m peering into someone else’s high school reunion.

&nbsp;

Ian MacKaye is a punk legend, even beyond DC But he’s remained in his hometown for his whole life, returning to this city after every tour. He has donated most of the proceeds from his albums and shows to local causes and non-profits. His bands sang about homelessness and police violence, and the money they made from recordings went to shelters and public health clinics in D.C.

MacKaye began as the frontman for the Teen Idles during high school, a band that has been labelled one of the first DC hardcore bands. After high school, the Teen Idles disbanded and he and several friends started a new band, Minor Threat. It was the early ’80s, and DC was experiencing the AIDs crisis and had just been introduced to crack cocaine. MacKaye had grown up the son of a newspaper editor, in the affluent Glover Park neighborhood on the northwest side of the city. DC was, and still is, one of the most racially and economically segregated cities in the country; the northwest is full of lush parks and independent bookstores, the southeast is a flat, tree-less land where the blocks of row houses are often described as blighted.

Minor Threat only made it three years before disbanding in 1983; their most significant legacy was arguably the coining of “straight-edge,” the now-ubiquitous term for leading a drug-, alcohol- (and often meat-) free life. In Minor Threat’s hit song, “Straight Edge,” MacKaye sang: “I’m a person just like you/ but I’ve got better things to do/ than sit around and fuck my head.” The song, based in MacKaye’s personal philosophy of sober living (defined as abstaining from alcohol, drugs, and casual sex), spread a new punk ethos; straight edge was an attempt to broach the occasional nihilism of punk music and connect it with a radical politics that called for active personal and systemic change. Straight edge has persisted as a punk subculture ever since.

MacKaye went on to form Fugazi in 1987, a much more musically coherent band with the same punk ethos. Shows were still only five dollars, and all the money raised went to the causes MacKaye and bandmates were singing about. The band members were older, and so was their audience. MacKaye was no longer screaming about staying straight to high schoolers; he and his band crafted measured but still chaotic tirades about the state of the city. In “Cashout” (2001), MacKaye sings about corruption and eminent domain: “It’s official/ development wants this neighborhood /gone so the city just wants the same/ talking about process and dismissal/forced removal of the people on the corner.”

Fugazi hit it big, but they never left Dischord Records. Until they disbanded in 2003, they continued playing cheap shows in small venues in DC and all over the world, always donating the majority of their proceeds. They wouldn’t allow audience members to mosh or slam dance because aggressive dancing often hurt women and younger audience members. They mainly played in all-ages venues, and didn’t sell albums or merchandise at their shows to avoid commercialization of their music.

In 2001, just before Fugazi broke up, MacKaye and Farina formed The Evens. After playing in huge venues with Fugazi, some of which relied heavily on alcohol sales to furnish profit, MacKaye was interested in splitting off from any reliance on the commercial music scene. MacKaye and Farina dealt with this by keeping their set almost acoustic, which lowered their production costs and made it so that they could play anywhere with little equipment.

&nbsp;

The anachronism of a camera-less show is kind of exciting, kind of uncomfortable, when I realize how much time I spend documenting my daily existence and then disseminating it via social media. For my generation, attending a show without being able to digitally capture a memento might almost defeat the purpose of being there, but as I look around I realize that my five friends and I are the only people of our age present. Most attendees look to be in their forties or fifties, save for the gaggle of under-ten year olds on the stage, assumedly the children of older attendees.

The stage looks almost like a living room, with a small rug under the drum set and two floor lamps framing MacKaye and Farina, though I have no photographs to remind me of the exact set-up. A red DC hardcore flag has been pinned up on the wall behind the duo; the triple stars of the district’s official banner replaced with the straight-edge triple X.

On one side of the stage, a group of eclectically-dressed children has gathered, some wiggling around to the music, others still and focused intently on the band as the play. One boy has closed his eyes as he mouths along with the words. All of the kids are wearing lavishly large and brightly colored protective headphones, a sure sign of their parents’ punk-rock status. I assume one is Carmine Francis, MacKaye and Farina’s four-year-old son, but I’m not sure which, because all of the kids seem to be intimately familiar with the lyrics to the songs. Some jam out on complex air-guitars; at the end of each song a few boys yell out requests.

Their favorite seems to be “Wanted Criminals,” a song about the police and private prison industry; the admittedly catchy chorus repeats “jails in search of criminals” over a furious guitar riff. MacKaye plays the song at the request of the cheering children; but not before prefacing it with a lengthy pontification on the role of the police in DC. A few minutes into his thoughts, he pauses and looks out at the audience. “I promise I don’t think about the police all the time.” Farina cocks her eyebrows and chuckles, “That is just not true.”

&nbsp;

It’s hard to imagine, looking at Arlington, VA, now, that in 1981, MacKaye’s record label, Dischord Records, moved their operations to a small bungalow home there because it was less expensive than renting space in the District. I grew up in Arlington, a fairly affluent and loudly liberal suburb just across the Potomac River from DC. The metro corridor of Arlington—the central urban areas of the city built up around the DC metro stops—is now replete with high-rise condos, shiny townhouses and upscale chain stores.

Dischord Records operated out of a small house only blocks away from this metro corridor for over twenty years; it was outfitted with a practice space, a design studio, and a darkroom over the years, and temporarily housed many DC punks and passers-through. The house, still owned by MacKaye but out of use as Dischord’s base, is tucked behind unassuming suburban shrubbery only a few miles from the house where I grew up. Minor Threat played at least a few shows in my high school’s cafeteria in the ’80s.

&nbsp;

I started listening to MacKaye’s music in the eighth grade, when a boy I had a huge crush on made me a mix CD with some Fugazi songs on it. I rocked out to “Give Me the Core” with my dad while driving to school in the morning, trying to cultivate the appropriate punk-rockness to impress the object of my affection.

In high school, I fell into the burgeoning DC punk youth scene. In December of my freshman year, I went to Positive Youth Fest for the first time, a weekend of punk shows and DIY workshops at a space called the Warehouse Next Door. I never really figured out how to blend into the punk aesthetic, but I went to Positive Youth Fest every year of high school, and even helped to organize it my junior year. This iteration of DC punk was just as angry as their ’80s forebears, and many of them had embraced that generation’s straight-edge lifestyle, but the two scenes seemed be glancing at each other across some sort of generational chasm.

The DIY punk shows I attended were overwhelmingly young; the main point of overlap with the still extant punks of the ’80s was St. Stephen’s Church, an Episcopalian church and occasional show venue in Columbia Heights. St. Stephen’s, which was MacKaye’s family’s church in the seventies, serves as the unofficial headquarters for Positive Force DC, an activist collective headed mainly by a cadre of 80s punk rockers. Ian MacKaye had his fiftieth birthday party at the church in March of 2012. St. Stephen’s also has served as a venue for two Positive Youth Fests, as well as a variety of other shows populated mainly by the under-25 generation.

&nbsp;

For an aspiring punk with a dislike for screaming and mosh-pits, The Evens, with their incisively political lyrics delivered in a pared-down style, played exactly the kind of music I wanted to embrace. They sang about DC politics, police brutality, gentrification, depression, apathy. The tried and true punk topics were now hushed and crooned, so soft you could miss the anger if you weren’t listening to the words.

Their newest album, <em>The Odds</em>, features their reliably melodic condemnations, mellow and raging all at once. The photograph on the album’s front cover shows an almost-silhouette of their son running toward the camera, foregrounded against the green, billowing shrubbery of what is probably the National Mall. The Capitol building looms in the background, a subtle reminder of the intrinsic geography in all of The Evens’ music. The album cover highlights the fact that these aging rockers are now, first and foremost, parents. But the content of the album reminds listeners that having a kid doesn’t make you forget about how fucked up things are; if anything, MacKaye and Farina now have even more of a stake in improving DC’s future.

In an interview with NPR in December, the interviewer asked MacKaye and Farina what it would mean for them to have a rebellious kid. Farina answered, “Well, he wanted to be a police officer for Halloween.”

MacKaye paused a little bit longer before answering. “I remember being in high school and being struck by, like, the rebels,” he said. “Like, the rebellious people were largely the people who were self-destructing. And it seemed, like, what a shame. That’s their only option in this culture, that you have to destroy yourself? And I thought, well, that’s just ridiculous. But, honestly, I haven’t really thought about—I mean, right now, like, what does our son have to do to rebel? He has to take 25 minutes to put his shoes on. That’s a form of rebellion that will drive you crazy, you know?”

Punk is still alive in DC, in a youth culture where new bands are constantly being formed and shows are being organized. But it also lives in the continued work of activists like Positive Force DC and musicians like MacKaye, who continue to produce challenging, political, pissed-off music even, as they become the parental authority to potential future punks.

<strong>MEGAN HAUPTMAN B’14.5</strong> was a police officer for Halloween.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Punk Never Dies—It just Gets Old]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8221</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-08 15:41:04</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="arts"><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[8224]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Providence Place</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8228</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8228</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[by Benson Tucker

Place is all of the things that make somewhere have the same characteristics year after year. These maps illustrate some financial elements of place that constitute the local framework for wealth, poverty, and the segregation of the two.

<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/maps-1.png"><a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/maps-11.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8230" title="maps 1" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/maps-11.png" alt="" width="496" height="727" /></a></a>

<strong>LOW-INCOME HOUSING</strong>

Michael Stumpf B’13 used data from a 2006 affordable housing bond to map federal low-income housing subsidies. He found discouraging patterns in their dispersion across the city. Low-income housing tax credits provide developers with a subsidy for offering housing to people earning under 50 or 60 percent of a county’s average income. These different thresholds correspond to different fractions of the available housing units: a development where 20 percent of residents make less than half of the area median income would be eligible for tax credits for each of those units. These thresholds suggest an agenda of promoting mixed income levels among residents of the same place.

However, that’s not how the program plays out in Providence. Most developments getting credits are 100 percent low-income, and receive credits for every unit. Since low-income eligibility is based on the county average, there are individual neighborhoods where most residents are below the low-income line. That’s where the affordable housing ends up. Describing his findings, Stumpf wrote in an email, “Rhode Island’s Five Year Strategic Housing Plan has contributed to an increased concentration of affordable housing within poorer neighborhoods.” Subsidies, then, aren’t accomplishing something qualitatively different from the market, just making it more extreme.

Elmwood (shown in the southern detail) is one such neighborhood, and, sure enough, it is home to several developments receiving credits for all units. Yet housing in Elmwood is largely affordable even without the subsidy, since most of the people living there earn low incomes. Figuring out how to promote low-income housing outside of predominantly low-income areas remains a challenge.

The maps also show that the tax credits are more dispersed in poor neighborhoods than in wealthier ones. Using a “spatial clustering” metric, Stumpf quantified the points’ spread within each neighborhood and found a direct correlation between concentration and land value. The cause of the clustering, Stumpf writes, is that in wealthier neighborhoods “developers constructed large apartment complexes with a minimum number of affordable units in order to qualify for LIHTCs.”

What’s more, Stumpf explains, the credits “tended to be in neighborhoods with already low amounts of residential zoning.” That is, the housing credits provided affordable housing not only where land prices were already low but also where residential areas most abutted commercial and industrial uses.

&nbsp;

<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/maps-2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8231" title="maps 2" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/maps-2.png" alt="" width="504" height="655" /></a>

<strong>UNDERBANKING</strong>

Comparing traditional banks to alternative financial services like check-cashers and payday loans, Ian Trupin B’13 realized how little overlap there is between each banking type’s territories. “AFS [Alternative Financial Services] is a blanket term including money orders, check cashing, payday lending, tax-refund anticipation lending, pawnshop lending, and rent-to-own programs,” Trupin explained. Takes on AFS tend to fall in one of two camps: consumer advocates point out exorbitant fees without any path to financial stability, while others (including some economists) argue that AFS provide a valuable service for emergency situations.

The question of why people turn to AFS is not entirely speculative, though. A 2009 survey found that physical convenience was the number one reason that “underbanked” people—those who use AFS despite having bank accounts—turned to these businesses. This question of convenience led Trupin to analyze the ways that banks and AFS fit into the Providence landscape, mapping the institutions’ immediate surrounding areas before turning to the city’s street network. In the street map, each bit of road is shaded according to whether a bank or an AFS is the shortest driving distance; the broken-up lines, where an AFS is closest, cover most of the city.

According to Trupin, the maps show that “the areas of the city which are most conspicuously dominated by AFS are characterized by lower income and minority-majority neighborhoods.” But a comparison with Newport News, VA—where underbanking rates are nearly twice as high—showed that street convenience doesn’t explain differences in underbanking rates. In Newport News, 44 percent of streets are closer to banks than AFS, while the figure in Providence is only 37 percent.

The issue, then, goes deeper than geography. On its website, AFS industry leader Ace Cash Express gives some other reasons why their customers choose them: “For [many] Americans, the business model of the traditional bank does not work....The lack of a nearby branch, or multi-lingual tellers and limited hours of operation, further contribute to the disenfranchisement of these Americans. Some simply do not feel welcome or comfortable inside a bank.” For a real understanding of AFS, we should also examine how banks might be keeping people out.

In Roman Polanski’s 1974 film <em>Chinatown</em>, a cop recounts his days working in Chinatown. When trouble broke out, they would sit on their hands, unable to say for sure who were the heroes and who were the villains. The complicated questions of affordable housing and AFS risk leaving us similarly confused, complicity washing through the whole process. The better lesson might be that institutions aren’t good or bad based on their mission statements so much as through their role within larger systems.

<strong>Benson Tucker B’13</strong> is lost in space.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[From the Geography Desk ]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8228</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-08 16:19:26</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-08 16:19:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>providence-place</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="metro"><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[8231]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Week on the Border</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8235</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 15:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8235</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/WiRBorderJPEG.jpg"><a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/WiRBorderJPEG1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8238" title="WiRBorderJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/WiRBorderJPEG1-175x300.jpg" alt="" width="175" height="300" /></a>
</a>by Rick Salame &amp; Alex Sammon

<strong>BUTTERFLY KISS(INGER)</strong>

<strong> </strong>They have no visas and don’t pay customs. This winter there were some 60 million of them: Monarch butterflies, flying south into Mexico for some fun in the sun. They’re perhaps the only border- crossing demographic to see a drop in numbers over the past couple decades. A March 14 statement by the World Wildlife Fund (WWF) confirmed that this winter’s migration was 59% smaller than last year’s and the smallest in 20 years. No one taught these butterflies political geography, so the main reason for the drop in Mexico’s winter population lies outside its borders.
<div>

According to Dr. Chip Taylor of the University of Kansas, American farmers’ increased use of the herbicide glyphosate has dramatically reduced the prevalence of milkweed, the monarchs’ dietary staple, in their Midwestern summer habitat. The result is
a dramatic decrease in the butterfly population, which threatens ecosystems across the continent, as well as Mexico’s ecotourism industry. Plus, searching the sky for a massive swarm of orange butterflies is just about the only thing that could make the four-hour wait at San Ysidro Border Inspection Station bearable.

Mexico has done its best to protect the itinerant butterflies; the government launched a highly successful anti-logging campaign in 2003 to protect the monarchs’ winter habitat. The campaign coupled police patrols with programs intended to involve rural residents in the ecotourism industry. But alas, Mother Nature hath made the butterflies migratory, meaning that Mexico can’t do much about the problem without the cooperation of the United States in restocking the Midwest with milkweed. “The conservation of monarch butterflies is a responsibility shared by Mexico, the US and Canada,” said Omar Vidal, director of World Wildlife Fund-Mexico, in the March 14 statement. “Mexico is doing its part. It is necessary that the US and Canada also do their part and protect the habitat of the monarch in their countries.” Mr. Vidal underestimates the extent of American apathy when it comes to butterflies.

The United States is more than happy to cooperate with the Mexican government in managing the flow of people and drugs across the border, but butterflies are just not on the political agenda. The fact remains, however, that the border between Mexico and the US is wide open for all sorts of crossings. Maybe it’s time for the two governments to start talking more often, before the little orange lepidoptera fall through the diplomatic cracks, somewhere near El Paso. —RS

<strong>LUCHA EN AMERICA </strong>
<div>

Lucha Libre is huge in Mexico. And it’s about to blow up in the States.

This week marked the signing of a massive promotional deal between the league of masked Mexican wrestlers and American in- vestment group FactoryMade Ventures. FactoryMade intends to inte- grate Lucha Libre into the American sports and entertainment world, with a series of live events and pay-per-view television displays.

Lucha Libre is Mexico’s second most watched sport after soccer, with 1,000 live events annually, five hours of television programming per week, and millions of tickets sold. That’s not to mention the tele- vision viewership of over 52 million that tunes in to see a world of wrestling in which weight class is irrelevant, and the athletes compete not just for physical superiority, but for a handful of winnings. These spoils include the ability to remove the mask from the loser (mascara contra mascara), the right to shave the loser’s head (mascara contra cabellera), and the right to literally end the losing wrestler’s career (mascara contra carrera). The stakes are incredibly high and the hair- care is remarkably questionable.

Following in the footsteps of Jack Black’s memorable performance as Nacho Libre in the movie of the same title, FactoryMade believes exporting this phenomenon across the border to an American audi- ence is a no-brainer. Despite the incredible saturation of the live wrestling market the rival World Wrestling Entertainment (WWE) (two matches a day, everyday), FactoryMade seems to think there’s growth potential. They’ve even booked events at New York’s Madison Square Garden and the Los Angeles Sports Arena.

If nothing else, Lucha Libre should provide an intriguing al- ternative to the WWE. With tired icons like Hulk Hogan and the Undertaker, predictable stunts like the chair smash, and a racially ho- mogeneous cast of wrestlers and viewers, there seems no reason more progressive wrestling fans would not turn to Lucha Libre, whose cast of 250 colorful characters includes a homosexual wrestler in drag (Cassandro, “Queen of the Ring”). There’s even a “mini estrellas” division, designed for wrestlers fewer than five feet in height.

While it remains to be seen whether or not the two leagues can live in harmony, Lucha Libre certainly brings a bit more diversity to the table. While the WWE caters to a primarily white, Midwestern and Eastern audience, the Lucha Libre franchise seems to have its sights set on Mexican-American populations on the West Coast. In any case, a little more stylized wrestling has never done anyone any harm. —AS

</div>
<strong>
</strong>

</div>
<strong> </strong>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8235</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-12 15:47:26</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-12 15:47:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>week-on-the-border</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="week-in-review"><![CDATA[Week in Review]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Growing Ca$h</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8246</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8246</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GrowingCash1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8251" title="GrowingCash" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GrowingCash1-300x227.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="227" /></a>

by Anna Rotman &amp; Emma Wohl
<div>
<div>

if you could design your own money, what would you put on it? Michael Giroux found inspiration from nature when designing Providence’s first alternative currency—CropCash. The smallest denomination is a honeycomb, the next a tide. Giroux is a member of the Fertile Underground Natural Cooperative and the designer of CropCash.The term currency is a stretch, Giroux told the <em>Independent</em>, given that it is not “money authorized by law.” The hand-stamped cards could never be confused for dollars, but that’s not the point: CropCash is a complimentary system of exchange.

The Fertile Underground runs a garden, a grocery store, a cafe, a work share, and soon a food truck, but this is their most ambitious project. The notes are already in use within the cooperative but are expected to take off on a larger scale in the next few months. CropCash is the printed form of Comb, a unit of currency based on labor; 3 Comb are worth roughly a day’s labor in any field. According to Giroux, it can be “used in interactions where dollars aren’t necessary.” But in interactions where buyers and sellers exchange goods, CropCash works the same as cash, even if it is only accepted within a designated network of businesses. Shoppers at Fertile Underground’s store on Westminster can use a combination of CropCash, dollars, and credit.

Local currencies have been developed in towns in Massachusetts, New York, and Connecticut. Stephanie Malin, a community sociologist at Brown University’s
Urban Environmental Lab, told the Independent that micro- currencies are a way for communities to assert independence from a global economy that doesn’t serve local needs. In
most situations, the currency doesn’t replace the legal tender. Instead, consumers can opt in, purchase the alternative cash, and spend it at participating businesses. It gives participants the incentive to invest in the local economy instead of purchasing from larger corporations; WalMart Neighborhood Markets don’t accept local currencies, nor are their profits ever seen by their host communities. Proponents of alternative currencies hope that producers paid in local currency will in turn spend this cash on regional products and services and continue a cycle of growth.

Khym Carmichael, one of the cooperative’s 13 member- owners, came to Providence from Ithaca, New York, a town with one of the longest-running forms of alternative currency in the U.S. She expressed concern over the way the dollar arbitrarily fluctuates, obscuring the value of basic goods like food. CropCash, on the other hand, reflects what producers’ and laborers’ “energy is really worth.” Malin explained how micro-currencies like CropCash are a form of money that reflects local values, values “that have thus far been externalized in the global financial system.”

</div>
<div>

We can’t all print money, though. One of the biggest obstacles this movement faces is how to convince would-be participants that these new currencies will be immune to inflation. Giroux’s solution is to base the number of notes printed on the real value of groceries in the store. Unlike the dollar, which is based on debt, CropCash is backed by the promise of goods available now. If all the participants wanted to exchange their CropCash today, they would have access to the $25,000 worth of groceries at Fertile Underground’s store; Giroux says he plans to cap the total amount in circulation after the next round of production at 400 Comb (the equivalent of $10,000).

It can be bought in the store at $25 per Comb, or $5 for one-fifth Comb. So far, the currency functions mostly as a gift card and a way of investing in the cooperative, since only Fertile Underground itself officially accepts it. But Giroux and Carmichael are hopeful about its expansion. By next season, which starts mid-summer, Giroux hopes to have half
a dozen businesses in Providence accepting CropCash. Even though it’s only accepted at one business now, he emphasized, it can also be used in personal interactions outside the store. He gave an example: a man came in to buy some groceries with CropCash his landlord had given him after he shovelled snow during a blizzard. This wasn’t an official transaction with a predetermined monetary value; the man just helped out during a blizzard. It’s hard to imagine all workers accepting their wages in a resource with such limited use. Still, such a transaction guarantees that capital remains within the community. If given their space, micro-currencies can become a community institution. In some cities, established local currencies are acceptable tender at community banks and credit unions. In others, they can be used to pay partial taxes. Don’t be fooled by the playful colors and charming names; CropCash means business.

<strong>BerkShares</strong>

Stockbridge Mohicans, W.E.B. Du Bois, Herman Melville, and Norman Rockwell are all pictured on BerkShares notes, the alternative currency of the Berkshires in western Massachusetts. Over three million BerkShares have been issued since they were launched in 2006. Among the things you can buy with them at over 400 businesses: a teeth cleaning, a wedding ring, and a limousine ride. Each Mohican (one BerkShare) costs $.95, which gives consumers a five percent discount on all purchases made with the local currency. This gives businesses taking BerkShares the incentive to keep the Normans circulating—by paying their distributors with them, for example—instead of cashing them in for dollars.

</div>
<div>

<strong>Ithaca Hours</strong>

Ithaca hours, used at over 900 businesses in Ithaca, New York, is one of the country’s longest-running forms of alternative currency. The term “hours” implies that the system rewards time spent in service to the city and “builds our community pride and connections,” according to the Ithaca Hours website. When the currency began in 1991, the minimum hourly wage in Tompkins County in upstate New York was 10 dollars, and that’s still its value to this day. The general rule is that one Hour is worth one hour’s work, but it’s up to those involved in the transaction to decide. Businesses determine what percentage of a purchases can be paid in Hours, and employees at some local businesses have agreed to accept partial wages in Hours. Ithaca Hours’ time- based economic system is a widespread phenomenon, one step beyond barter, which allows person-to-person transactions without relying on the Federal Reserve to determine currency’s value. Recently, however, the use of Hours has begun to decline, most likely because Paul Glover, the inventor of Ithaca Hours and one of its most dedicated evangelists, moved out of the town. Fewer businesses accept it, and the rise of electronic banking over cash exchange has made it seem retrograde. Others have stepped in to fill Glover’s shoes, but the future of a local currency once so successful it attracted the interest of one of Beijing’s largest think-tanks is now unclear.

<strong>rCredit</strong>

According to their website, the ‘r’ stands for “Regenerative, Revolutionary, Responsible Resilience.” They are set to launch their trial runs in Greenfield, MA and New London, CT in the upcoming months. The credits are sold on par with the US dollar and are circulated entirely electronically. The creators see themselves as the next generation of alternative currencies: sales will be tracked online to monitor RCredit circulation so that stores will not end up with a stockpile of credits they can’t unload. The non- profit that runs rCredit, Common Good Finance, hopes to eventually expand to towns across the Northeast.

<strong>ANNA ROTMAN B’ 14.5 &amp; EMMA WOHL B’ 14</strong> are worth the energy.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8246</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 21:44:47</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 21:44:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>growing-cah</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Auditory Input</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8256</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 21:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8256</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Providence-Talks-JPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8257" title="Providence Talks JPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Providence-Talks-JPEG-300x226.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="226" /></a>

by Simon Engler
<div>
<div>

Dr. James Morgan, a brown university developmental psychologist who studies early childhood language acquisi- tion, holds up a pair of toddler’s overalls. They are patterned with bright circles; on the chest section is a snap-close pouch, about the size of the deck of cards. It looks like something might fit inside.

“Yes,” Dr. Morgan says, “this is the garment for the de vice.”

The device is a digital language processor (DLP), a compact sensor developed by the Colorado-based Language Environment Analysis Foundation (LENA). DLPs are record- ing devices that count spoken words. They are designed to be worn by young children. Plug a Digital Language Processor into a computer equipped with LENA’s software, and you will generate a complete picture of the audible language to which its wearer has been exposed. That means the total number of words heard in a day, along with the origin of those words and their frequency.

This is the technology behind Mayor Angel Taveras’s most recent city initiative, Providence Talks, which aims to improve language skills of young children in the city’s poorest families. The initiative was Providence’s winning entry to the Mayor’s Challenge, a contest organized by Bloomberg Philanthropies which offered nine million dollars in funding to municipal governments with innovative plans for urban improvement. Providence, which took first place on March 13, was awarded five million dollars; Chicago, Philadelphia, Houston, and Santa Monica took one million dollars each. Now, Mayor Taveras and City Hall hope to improve the language ability of Providence’s youngest through a venture into the technology of developmental psychology. researchers have been aware of the linguistic deficiency of young children from low-income families since the mid- 1960s. Thirty years later, in 1995, Betty Hart and Todd Ris- ley, authored Meaningful Differences in the Everyday Experience of Young American Children, the most comprehensive study on the subject. According to their analysis, children from families on welfare were typically exposed to millions of fewer words than their wealthier counterparts by age four.

This inequity has serious effects. Children with insufficient exposure to spoken language take longer to understand the meanings of the sentences they hear. Extracting ideas from the jumble of sounds and pitches that make up language is an incredibly complex process, and mastering it demands practice—lots of it. According to the work of Hart and Risley, ideal linguistic development requires children to be exposed to at least 21,000 words per day. What the words are isn’t particularly important. Furthermore, all languages are equally beneficial to development, and so LENA’s technology is programmed to recognize both English and Spanish. What counts in linguistic development is exposure, not variety. Simply put, the more a parent speaks to a child, the more that child will learn.

</div>
<div>

Linguistic development is time-sensitive. Only up to age four are most children’s brains wired for rapid language ac- quisition. That’s why children with a low exposure to spoken language at an early age end up having difficulty extracting ideas from words—and, thus, performing well—in elementary school. Providence’s grade-school literacy rates speak for them- selves—the city has a problem. According to the Rhode Island Department of Education, only one out of every three children in the district begins kindergarten at an appropriate literacy level. And economically disadvantaged students in city elementary schools have on average tested at lower read- ing levels than their classmates in every year since 2003.

LENA’s technology won’t improve the language skills of Providence children by itself. As Dr. Morgan, the Brown University psychologist, told the Independent, a DLP “does absolutely nothing” on its own. It simply produces data. But Providence officials hope to use that data to dramatically impact the way parents interact with their children. According to Toby Shepherd, the Mayor’s deputy direc- tor of policy, eligibility for participation in Providence Talks will coincide with eligibility for general visitation from the Department of Health. Families will be targeted based on a preexisting newborn screening process testing for devel- opmental disorders that is administered in Rhode Island hospitals. Families deemed eligible for general home visitation services during the screening process would likewise qualify for participation in Providence Talks. Engagement with the program will be free and voluntary, and to ensure user privacy, only abstract data about word count and word origins—and not actual audio recordings—will be stored on DLPs.

The next step will be the delivery of DLPs to participating families. Workers from the Department of Health will instruct parents in the use of the device, which must be worn for a few days each month for the necessary data to be retrieved. Later, workers will return to households to pick up the DLPs for processing at a central location. Finally, the processed information will be returned to families. DOH workers will review the results with parents, explain their significance, and discuss potential strategies for improvement, like interactive games, bedtime stories, and creative play. After that, the responsibility for change will lie with households. DOH workers will encourage families to take the education of their young children into their own hands, but the program will not prescribe particular educational activities to the families it will serve. As Shepherd told the Independent, “This is about empowering parents.”

</div>
<div>

Pilot studies have proven the effectiveness of this strategy. According to a statement released by the Mayor’s Office, parents who learn that their children have not been exposed to enough language tend to increase their word usage by an average of 55 percent. The effects of such an increase can be enormous. IQ levels in children are strongly correlated with language exposure. In fact, Risley and Hart pointed out that language exposure out- strips all other variables—including socioeconomic status—as a predictor of juvenile intelligence. And the benefits extend to all speakers of all languages.

Only a few children will be enrolled in Providence Talks in the coming year, but by 2018, City Hall hopes to have ex- panded the program’s reach to nearly 3,000 families. Bloom- berg Philanthropies, which funds the program, has encour- aged other cities to consider following Providence’s example. As Toby Shepherd, the Mayor’s deputy director of policy, told the <em>Independent</em>, “it’s a pretty novel program, and it could be replicated.” With funding and planning, programs like Providence’s could improve the language ability of children across the country.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8256</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 21:53:06</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 21:53:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>auditory-input</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Painting the Corners</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8260</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8260</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/VinScullyJPEG.jpg"></a><a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/VinScullyJPEG1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8263" title="VinScullyJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/VinScullyJPEG1-296x300.jpg" alt="" width="296" height="300" /></a>

by Tristan Rodman
<div>
<div>
<div></div>
<div>I went to my first baseball game at age five. My dad’s friend, who had taken it upon himself to make me a baseball fan, led me up the many steps to the Reserve Level of Dodger Stadium. For what felt like miles, all I could see were the backs of fans filing into the stadium. Before the turnstile, he turned to me and waxed poetic: it might take a lot of walking to get there, but the baseball diamond is a magical space, a sanctuary, an escape. A few minutes later, the sea of backs parted. I stood in the stadium concourse, looking out. I saw emerald green grass with a tan diamond, framed in 16:9 cinema perspective by two large pillars and the grandstand of the upper deck—a near-panoramic view of the field’s expanse, from foul line to foul line.Baseball is all about framing. Baseball’s graphic representation is the box score, which organizes statistical information and game summaries into frames for newsprint. Catchers frame pitches to make them look closer to the strike zone than they actually are. Innings, the sport’s basic temporal unit, are also called frames. There is one man who has been framing the game for Dodgers fans for over half a century. That man is Dodgers broadcaster Vin Scully. Scully, an Irish Catholic born in the Bronx, started calling Dodger baseball in 1950 when the team was still based in Brooklyn. He moved with the Dodgers from Brooklyn to Los Angeles in 1957. When the Dodgers first came to LA, they lacked a proper stadium. The team played in the Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum, originally built for the 1932 Olympics. The space was so large and so improperly configured for baseball that fans began to bring transistor radios to the ballpark, both to learn about the players on their newfound home team and to aid in comprehending the action on the field. Vin Scully introduced Los Angeles to its Dodgers.&nbsp;

Scully calls the game both for radio and television. He frames the lives of his listeners, bringing continuity to LA’s disjointed spaces of work, car, and home. As Robert Creamer explains in <em>Sports Illustrated</em>, “When a home-rushing driver bogs down in a classic freeway traffic jam, he finds that nothing else is as soothing as Vin Scully’s voice describing the opening innings of a Dodger night game just getting under way.  A man who drives home from work, his suit hanging on his shoulders listening to an exciting game is not about to abandon it when he reaches his house. As a result, millions of southern Californians have Vin Scully with their supper.”

Scully is rarely seen from the waist down. At the beginning of every Dodgers broadcast, we’re graced with the same shot. The camera captures Scully’s cherubic smile. A pocket square peeking out matches his well-pressed shirt. He stands in front of the emerald green, framed in 16:9 cinema perspective, the near-panoramic expanse of the stadium as his backdrop. He has the best seat in the house, as if he’s right there in the concourse, one fan among many, yet still above the rest. He is the Los Angeles Dodgers’ omniscient narrator.

</div>
<div>

Every night he welcomes us: “Hi, everybody, and a very pleasant good evening to you, wherever you may be.” And with that, he begins the next chapter in the Dodgers’ story. In his study of nationalism, <em>Imagined Communities</em>, Benedict Anderson links the origins of nationalism to the development of the novel. According to Anderson, the form of the novel presents a type of storytelling that allows for simultaneity, an experience of time that connects otherwise disconnected peoples. The novel hinges on the use of “meanwhile,” the use of juxtaposition to tie many strands into one larger picture. Substitute fandom for nationalism, and Vin Scully’s narration becomes the backbone of baseball as novel.

Indeed, Scully has the rare ability to turn a game into a literary work. He constantly interrupts narratives with statistics or description of the action. There’s no set length for an at-bat in baseball; they can last anywhere from twenty seconds to ten minutes. Scully has mastered the art of fitting an entire story into a flexible timeline. He does this with an expert use of “meanwhile.” He juggles and weaves the stories of the hitter, the pitcher, their history together, the batter on-deck, the runners-on-base, and the coaches standing behind them. A continuous flow, interrupted only by the breaks between innings. An excerpt from the ninth inning of Sandy Koufax’s 1965 perfect game:

<em>Here is Joe Amalfitano to pinch-hit for Don Kessinger. Amalfitano is from Southern California, from San Pedro. He was an original bonus boy with the Giants. Joey’s been around, and as we mentioned earlier, he has helped to beat the Dodgers twice, and on deck is Harvey Kuenn. Kennedy is tight to the bag at third, the fastball, a strike. Oh and one with one out in the ninth inning, one to nothing, Dodgers. Sandy reading, into his windup and the strike one pitch: curveball, tapped foul, oh and two. And Amalfitano walks away and shakes himself a little bit, and swings the bat. And Koufax with a new ball, takes a hitch at his belt and walks behind the mound. I would think that the mound at Dodger Stadium right now is the loneliest place in the world. Sandy fussing, looks in to get his sign, oh and two to Amalfitano. The strike two pitch to Joe: fastball, swung on and missed, strike three. He is one out away from the promised land, and Harvey Kuenn is comin’ up. So Harvey Kuenn is batting for Bob Hendley. The time on the scoreboard is 9:44. The date, September the ninth, nineteen-sixty-five, and Koufax working on veteran Harvey Kuenn. Sandy into his windup and the pitch, a fastball for a strike. He has struck out, by the way, five consecutive batters, and that’s gone unnoticed. Sandy ready and the strike one pitch: very high, and he lost his hat. He really forced that one. That’s only the second time tonight where I have had the feeling that Sandy threw instead of pitched, trying to get that little extra, and that time he tried so hard his hat fell off — he took an extremely long stride to the plate— and Torborg had to go up to get it. One and one to Harvey Kuenn. Now he’s ready: fastball, high, ball two. You can’t blame a man for pushing just a little bit now. Sandy backs off, mops his forehead, runs his left index finger along his forehead, dries it off on his left pants leg. All the while Kuenn just waiting. Now Sandy looks in. Into his windup and the two-one pitch to Kuenn: swung on and missed, strike two. It is 9:46 p.m. Two and two to Harvey Kuenn, one strike away. Sandy into his windup, here’s the pitch: Swung on and missed, a perfect game.</em>

</div>
<div>

Scully then goes silent for a full 38 seconds, letting the crowd do his job for him. In an article for <em>Salon</em>, Gary Kaufman calls it “the best piece of baseball writing [he’s] ever seen,” made all the more impressive because, “it came off the top of his head, at a moment when, like the man whose feat he was describing, he knew he had to be at the top of his game.” Scully, like other great narratorial voices, has stylistic signatures: tight metaphor and a haunting use of silence. Bob Gibson “pitches like he’s double parked.” Tom Glavine is “like a tailor: a little off here, a little off there and you’re done, take a seat.” Statistics “are used much like a drunk uses a lamppost: for support, not illumination.” His use of language is clean and efficient, drawing from a tradition of radio broadcasting where it was necessary to paint a vivid image for an audience removed from any view of the field. He never lets linguistic flare get in the way of the moment, always backing away from the microphone when many broadcasters would seize the moment as an opportunity to define their own careers. After Koufax’s no-hitter, Scully let the crowd make the call. After Kirk Gibson’s walk-off home run in the 1988 World Series, Scully stayed mum as Gibson went all the way around the bases. When he finally spoke again, the words he chose carried so much weight that they’ve become, perhaps, his most notable: “In a year that has been so improbable, the impossible has happened.”

</div>
<div>

Scully’s past few years have seen a slight reduction in both workload and linguistic accuracy. When Matt Kemp and Jeff Kent batted back-to-back in 2008, Scully had particular trouble enunciating and distinguishing the two names. He no longer travels with the team east of the Rocky Mountains. Scully may no longer be as sharp, but he’s just as witty, carrying enthusiasm for new knowledge and technology in even greater proportion. During catcher A.J. Ellis’ sixth inning at-bat in a game against the Rockies on August 3, Scully launched into a passage about the new things he’d learned over the course of the season:

<em>You know this year, more than many years, I have a great deal of gratitude for the all the folks listening on radio and watching on television. Pitch in for a strike, one and one. For instance, earlier this year I learned about a soul patch—that little bit of beard. One ball, one strike. That’s a strike. One and two. Then of course, the great discovery.</em> [Rockies shortstop]<em> Troy Tulowitzki‘s hairdo: a mullet! Boy, that, that really put me in line. So now I know about a soul patch and a mullet. And then the other night, talked about a—a “tweet,” only I called it a “twit,” but I-I-I thought it was a “twit,” since it’s Twitter. A drive to the gap in left-center. There’s nobody there. It will drop for a base hit, and holding with the single is Ellis. So anyway, I’m really up to date now on Twitter. But I do think for all of you folks who are tweeting out there, you gotta get something TRENDING. WHOOOOA. So maybe we ought to get something trending about A.J. Ellis. And if you do that, you know what? I’m cool. I’m really cool.</em>

Dodgers fans responded to the call to action, and by Ellis’s next at-bat in the seventh, Scully let us know: “They’re trending, twittering, tweeting A.J. Ellis all over the US and to be honest they told me to say that. Ah, he’s a nice boy.” Ellis hit a home run on the next pitch. In Scully’s words:

<em>Manny Corpas, a veteran reliever, will now become the fourth pitcher for Chicago, facing A.J. Ellis of Twitter fame. Manny Corpas has certainly been around. Corpas inherited fourteen runners this year; four have scored. Manny is from Panama City in Panama. He’ll be thirty, December the third. Big man, six-three, lean, about one seventy-five and a slider hit to right center and deep. On his horse and watching it go over the wall is DeJesus. A.J. Ellis! He’s really got something trending</em>!

</div>
A few days later, Scully attempted to lipread a tirade from irate Rockies manager Jim Tracy, converting it into TV-appropriate language on the fly: “He caught the ball,” Jim says. “He caught the blinkin’ ball.” “He caught the darn ball.” [Tracy gets ejected]. Uh oh, he’s gone. He is gone. “That is blinkin’ fertilizer.” I’m doing the best to translate. “You’ve gotta be blinkin’ me.”

The 2013 baseball season will be Scully’s 64th and final season calling Dodgers games. He plans to retire at the end of the year, and even though this is his third attempt at retirement in as many years, the sense is that this year he’s for real. The past few years have been disappointing ones for the Dodgers, as they’ve suffered while Frank McCourt dragged the team through bankruptcy court, slashing payroll and fan confidence as he went. This year is the first full year for the Dodgers under a new ownership group, one that has drastically increased the payroll and improved talent, renewing the team’s commitment to a fanbase lost by the penny-pinching and pocket-lining of the McCourts. Scully came back to see the Dodgers contend. In Scully’s last year, he faces a steep task: bring a disenfranchised baseball community back to Los Angeles, where basketball and the possibility of a new football team reign supreme. If anybody can accomplish this, it’s Vin Scully, who once strung together a fanbase in Los Angeles where there previously was none.

Baseball is a particularly difficult game for many in our generation to embrace: it moves slowly, sometimes not at all. It’s modernity’s pastime, but we’re in the information age. If the NBA has taken so well to Twitter, it’s possible that baseball is still stuck in the newspaper box score. Frequently I’m asked, “Why do you like baseball?” Invariably, I have two answers. First, the 16:9 cinema perspective, the view from the top, the place where I go to freeze time in three-hour increments every summer. And the man who turns players into characters, seasons into stories, and makes me equally proud to be an Angelino and a Dodgers fan. It’s impossible to imagine anybody else greeting the fans on a breezy Wednesday in May: “Hi, everybody, and a very pleasant good evening to you, wherever you may be.”

<strong>TRISTAN RODMAN B’ 15 </strong>pitches like he’s double parked.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8260</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:04:50</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:04:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>painting-the-corners</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="sports"><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cups and Needles</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8266</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8266</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/HollisticJPEG.jpg"><a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/HollisticJPEG1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8269" title="HollisticJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/HollisticJPEG1-42x300.jpg" alt="" width="42" height="300" /></a>
</a>

by Alix Taylor
<div>

If you wind your way past a wholesale pottery store to 14 Imperial Place in Providence’s Jewelry District and climb up some of the narrowest stairs you’ll ever encounter, you’ll find yourself in the soothing oasis of Emerging Energy Acupunc- ture. Mary Claire Dilks, who opened the practice in 2004, sports purple cat eye glasses and looks perfectly at home in the multi-room suite. It’s painted in a soft blue with bamboo and the occasional Chinese scroll hanging on the walls. As the daughter of a new-age yoga mom who claims to have found her personal god in Hatha breathing, I had a natu- ral interest in the practice of holistic medicine, and Emerging Energy Acupuncture seemed like a good first stop. When I first called Mary Dilks to arrange our meeting I had no idea what to expect from a “licensed doctor of acupuncture and board certified Chinese herbologist.” But my ideas of integra- tive medicine as a crunchy fad were dispelled as Dilks and I discussed the growth of holistic and alternative medicine in Rhode Island. “Obviously if you have an emergency, go to the hospital; don’t come to me,” she told me, “but there are other answers for chronic pain and illness.”

“Sometimes Western medicine doesn’t quite cut it,” she told me, a sentiment that resounds throughout my conver- sations with holistic medicine practitioners. Dilks battled chronic fatigue through her teenage years, cycling through countless waiting rooms and blood tests. She felt trapped in her body, unable to experience the activities her peers enjoyed. Eventually, though, she discovered the power of alternative medicine.

Around that time, Dilks began to explore eastern philoso- phy and meditation, going on to receive her BA in Philosophy from Loyola in Chicago, and studying Chinese medicine at the Pacific College of Oriental Medicine. Her study of Chi- nese medicine moved her from the Chicago campus to New York City. From there she made her way to Providence, where she opened her practice, which includes acupuncture, cupping and diet and nutritional therapy. Acupuncture stimulates acupoints along 14 major energy channels to restore the bal- ance and flow of Chi in the body. Cupping, Dilks explains, targets those same pressure points along the 14 meridians with suction instead of needles.

“The majority of my patients come to me as a last resort. They’ve been dealing with issues like chronic pain for years before they make it to me,” Dilks says. Many times doctors will recommend her practice to patients who haven’t seen results from Western medicine. But according to the young practitioner, that’s starting to change: “I started my practice
at a good time in the culture. Lots of medical studies have been emerging proving the power of alternative medicine.” According to the National Center for Complementary and Alternative medicine, 3.1 million people tried acupuncture in 2007, one million more than in 2002, and those numbers are continuing to grow. Insurance companies are even starting to cover some of the cost of acupuncture, depending on the symptoms it treats. That trend may also draw more patients to Dilks, whose average rate is $120 for initial appointments and $75 per hour for follow-ups.

When I asked Dilks about the results she’s been able to achieve with acupuncture and diet, she told me the story of the youngest patient she’s treated in her practice. A seven- year-old boy came to Dilks’ office with extreme asthma, a condition he had been battling since he was under a year old. With herbs and acupuncture, Dilks was able to move him from breathing machine and multiple inhalers down to just the occasional inhaler.

“Suffering draws people to holistic care,” Karlo Burger told me over the phone. Dilks recommended that I contact Burger, a shiatsu practitioner and teacher who has been trying to build a community of hollistic healthcare practicioners in the Providence area. In 1999 Burger founded the Integrative Medicine Alliance, an independent non-profit network of “conventional and complementary/alternative medicine practitioners and people seeking healthcare.” He also maintains shiatsu practices in Providence and Cambridge, MA. In 2002, Rhode Island followed Minnesota’s lead and ad- opted the Unlicensed Healthcare Practices Act, which makes it easier for holistic practitioners like Burger to practice their healing methods. The act allows practitioners of healing techniques that do not include “surgery, x-ray radiation, prescrib- ing, administering, or dispensing legend drugs and controlled substances, practices that invade the human body by puncture of the skin, setting fractures,” as well as the practices of dentistry, chiropractic medicine, and acupuncture, to operate without a license. Similar statutes exist in California, Florida, and Idaho.
<div>

Burger explained shiatsu, a traditional Japanese healing art whose name translates as “finger pressure,” as acupunc- ture without needles. Unlike acupuncture, however, shiatsu doesn’t have a special certification requirement. Without the certification process, shiatsu has stayed out of the main- streamed holistic movements—as opposed to acupuncture and chiropractic medicine, which has a licensing procedure in all fifty states. Shiatsu remains, at most, a practice worked into the curriculum of massage schools. But Burger tries to work around that. Because insurance companies aren’t picking up the tab, Burger offers “community shiatsu,” a process in which couples or groups are diagnosed and trained by a professional, then practice treatments on each other. Because it happens in a group, it is more affordable than one-on-one treatments.

Both practitioners claimed the ease with which holistic practitioners can work in Rhode Island makes it difficult to build a community. “It’s impossible to get people together,” Dilks told me in her office. According to Dilks, there had been meetings to bring together the licensed doctors of acu- puncture in Rhode Island, but “typically people who practice acupuncture like to do their own thing.” Burger saw a similar response to his own initiative to bring together practitio- ners, “It’s like herding cats.” Burger noted that while the freedom Rhode Island allows for holistic practices to evolve and include interesting work like shiatsu and homeopathy, it also inhibits the possibility of growth brought on by unify- ing disparate practices in the community. Still, Burger speaks optimistically when discussing his practice in Rhode Island; the Unlicensed Healthcare Practices Act “follows a line of tolerance in the state dating back to Roger Williams.”

Alternative, complementary, or holistic medicine remains a field with many different courses of practice, of which Burger’s and Dilk’s are just two. The field as a whole seems
to be gaining more credence. In a June 2012 meeting of an advisory committee to the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services discussing the illness Chronic Fatigue Syn- drome, committee chair Gailen Marshall highlighted holistic medicine’s ability to adapt to individuals’ problems: “Too many times there’s an arrogance in Western medicine that says if we can’t give a pill or do a procedure, it’s not real and if it is real, it’s the patient’s problem, not the doctor’s. The holistic approach to care says that a person has a body, a person has a mind, and a person has a spirit—some people might call that a soul—and you must minister to all three of those to properly care for a patient.”

In between discussions of cutting-edge medical procedures, Marshall took time to show how alternative medical practices share common ideals with the broader medical community and encourage his fellows to treat it with an open mind. The care holistic practitioners give is based on “a Hippocratic principle that I was taught in the early ‘80s when I went to medical school. I continue to try to teach that to my trainees. While we espouse it, unfortunately, sometimes we talk the talk and we don’t walk the walk.”

<strong>ALIX TAYLOR B’ 15</strong> is more than a passing trend.

</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8266</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:10:49</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:10:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cups-and-needles</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Rite of Spring</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8272</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8272</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/RiteJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8274" title="RiteJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/RiteJPEG.jpg" alt="" width="435" height="540" /></a>

by Robert Sandler

I went to see the turned-in feet of Le Sacre moving still, under the curtain. Pagan Russia still moving Nijinsky’s flatness.
<div>

All the ballet made my friend vomit. I felt bad too, viscerally, on the shaped chairs, but I am not vomiting. I felt fine, good even. I felt as though I was looking at a painting while in the middle of a play, on stage, on a stone floor, with wool cinching at the shoulders of my fellow actors’ costumes.

Things are caught in muscle and skin. A scar. Tying a knot. The dancers had to loosen themselves, fill a space in their bodies for this history and enact this. I think that their rigidness was bound by this history. Their flatness was about representation, they moved between themselves.

It is very cold outside, but soon I will be able to say, “I am drinking beer in my apartment. I just made peas—they are sweet. Settle, or whatever you need to do, and then call me. Please.” This is because the weather should be changing soon.

When I got home from the ballet, I turned on the heat. Serena’s socks on top of the gray gas square caught on fire. I waved a towel and the fan started to rotate. Then I put the charred socks in her room and lay in my bed.

One of the men had very large thighs, we saw them, because he danced a lead role in the performances leading up to Le Sacre. Unable to sleep, I masturbated with thoughts of his legs.

Dancers are versed in a particular grammar and lexicon. They speak a language. Nijinsky gave his dancers a shallow language; they had to try and talk about life and death with their big toes turned towards one another. Their elbows are raised to their shoulders. When the sacrificed girl jumps, her knees point to the left, the legs do not come out from underneath her body.
<div>

The performance was an attempt at reconstructing the original choreography. It was discarded after the first performances; the original choreography remained untouched. The Joffrey ballet revived it in the 1987. Watching the ballet, you are watching 100 years forward trying to move 100 years back.

Can you see who moves like that?

Maybe my vomiting friend was filled with the Paris of 1913, and all the hissing was expelled from her.

My vomiting friend was a dancer. Maybe the hissing ghosts were expelled from her.

If you tie a knot, and you have before, a little ghost comes and crawls into your fingers.

An untrained body is making ghosts, fumbling towards a knot or a scar. A part of the body that remembers.

This is the picture from the photo booth at the theatre. Everyone is blurry except for my friend who was sick afterwards. So maybe we were ghosts too, in the moment, except for my friend, who was bound to the history we set about imbibing: the girl dancing herself to death, towards ghosts.
<div>

When I dance, I think about untrained bodies. I value them because this is the body that I have—it is awkward. I like the way that it is gangly. When I dance I try to find every beat with every part of my body.

The dancers in Le Sacre are often on seperate parts of the stage, in different circles. They follow different beats. Because of this, you can’t rehearse with one person yelling numbers. Each group follows their own bit of order.

The dancers in Le Sacre are asked to forget about their elongated limbs, about the elegance they have worked towards.

When I have performed in front of others, I have closed my eyes. Once, I ran into a wall with a deer spine wrapped around my arm.

When we were walking through Providence after Le Sacre the wind tried to bury itself in us. When I got home there was a skunk eating the food my landlord leaves out for the neighborhood cats. It looked at me.

Everyone is throwing up. If this is true, then maybe everyone is filled with ghosts, or maybe it wasn’t the ballet. Please stay hydrated. My friend is drinking Gatorade, maybe you could drink that too, ghosts or not.

&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8272</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:15:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:15:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-rite-of-spring</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Science and the State</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8277</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8277</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ScieandStateJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8278" title="ScieandStateJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ScieandStateJPEG-276x300.jpg" alt="" width="276" height="300" /></a>

&nbsp;

by John Aurelio
<div>
<div>

President Obama, in his State of the Union speech on Febru- ary 12, called for a new era of scientific discovery. “Now is the time to reach a level of research and development not seen since the height of the space race,” he declared. Yet just a few weeks after this bold call to action, the notorious sequester took effect, requiring $1.2 trillion in across-the-board spend- ing cuts. According to White House estimates, the sequestra- tion would cut US science budgets by 8.2 perecnt, with the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and NASA among the hardest hit. “The sequestration itself was never intended to be implemented,” the report from the White House’s Office of Management and Budget notes. But here we are bracing for the impact of such austerity.

Amidst such economic hardship, the difference in the opinions of the public and our elected officials regarding scientific issues suggests a fundamental shift in our national priorities. In last year’s presidential primaries, Gov. Rick Perry of Texas claimed that greedy scientists rest on faulty data “so that they will have dollars rolling into their projects.” For such claims, Dr. Kenneth Miller, Professor of Biology at Brown University, faults what he sees as the cynicism associated with science in the United States. “The easier it becomes to depict the scientific enterprise as a special interest,” writes Dr. Miller, “the easier it becomes to reject scientific findings.” However, remarks like Gov. Perry’s are not shuttered in partisan gratifi- cation; misinformation and slander emerge from every front along the political spectrum. Unfortunately for Democrats, their progressive political allies often hold blatantly anti- science beliefs. Reacting to a frenzy surrounding the swine-flu vaccine, the CDC and the White House pulled multi-dose swine flu shots because they contained thimerasol, even though there is absolutely no evidence that supports a causal link between thimerasol and autism.

Such examples illustrate the danger of scientific illiteracy. In a 2011 annual survey conducted by researchers at Yale and George Mason Universities, for example, 40 percent
of respondents agreed with the statement, “There is a lot of disagreement among scientists about whether or not global warming is happening.” This is a significant number in spite of the overwhelming consensus within the scientific commu- nity that global warming is, in fact, occurring. In a recently released study in Pediatrics, researchers examined parents’ reasons for not vaccinating their teenage daughters against HPV in 2008 through 2010. What the researchers found was a startling increase in the number of parents citing “Safety concerns/side effects” as their main factor. In 2008, it was 4.5 percent; by 2010, it had jumped to 16.4 percent.

This is not to say that science is without fault, its history brimming with missteps. Social Darwinism, for example, perverted the ideas of evolutionary science to uphold bigotry and racism. Regarding medical diagnoses, evidence-based reasoning has at times been overridden by cultural bias. There was once a time when physicians diagnosed mental illness and “idiocy” based solely on appearance. Allan Hamilton, MD in 1883’s Types of Insanity: An Illustrated Guide to the Diagnosis of Mental Disease: “When one walks through the wards of any asylum for the insane, he will be immediately impressed with the repulsiveness of the faces about him.”

</div>
<div>

<strong>Committee Chairs and Charlatans</strong>

Elected officials should make choices only after scrutiniz- ing the evidence presented. But this too is no guarantee of realistic policy. One stumbling block is the blatant ignorance shown by some politicians regarding scientific issues. Take, for example, Rep. Todd Akin, who serves on the House Science, Space, and Technology Committee. During his 2012 cam- paign, Akin remarked, “It seems to me, from what I under- stand from doctors, [that] if it’s a legitimate rape, the female body has ways to try to shut that whole thing down.” Not only is this view biologically unsound, it is a clear indication of his lack of scientific expertise. In spite of this, Akin served on a committee that dictates the future of our national science policy.

There are also politicians who view the world in ways that will never reconcile with scientific consensus. Rep. Paul Broun is a creationist who sits on the same committee as Akin. In a speech made on behalf of the Liberty Baptist Church, Broun proclaimed, “All that stuff I was taught about evolution and embryology and the Big Bang Theory, all that is lies straight from the pit of Hell.” The committee’s chair, Rep. Ralph Hall, lumps “global freezing” together with global warming, which he doesn’t believe humans can significantly impact. As he says, “I don’t think we can control what God controls.”

Yet even amidst such disparity in worldviews, these politi- cians return to the alleged menacing motives of science. On the same committee, Rep. Mo Brooks said of scientific findings regarding climate change,“We’re being asked to undermine America’s economy based on this guesswork specu- lation.” Rep. Brooks still trots out the same debunked no- tion that a scientific consensus existed in the 1970s on “global cooling,” which he portrays as a scare concocted by scientists “in order to generate funds for their pet projects.” Such anti- science sentiment, however, is not merely shut away in these committees. Rep. Dana Rohrabacher once suggested a ploy to cut greenhouse gas emissions by “subsidizing the clearing of rainforests.”

At the heart of such outspoken dribble is a fundamental disregard for the integrity of science. In the minds of such politicians, scientific beliefs do not turn on the weight of evi- dence, but on the clang of their coffers. It is not the search for knowledge that motivates the scientific process, but rather the aggrandizement of ivory tower charlatans. Amidst the clamor on Capitol Hill, science is merely another “lobby” vying for limited funds.

</div>
<div>

<strong>Law and Science</strong>

According to the cq roll call guide to the New Con- gress, law is the primary professional background of Senators today, followed by public service or politics, and then business or the corporate field. There is little doubt that the nine scientists in our government must strain for a voice amidst the clamor of two hundred lawyers. Although bolstered by the 32 medical professionals on Capitol Hill, the American govern- ment is markedly non-scientific. Congress is essentially a courtroom, and judging from the recent sequestration, science is not of the utmost priority.

Neil DeGrasse Tyson, astrophysicist and director of the Hayden Planetarium in New York City, criticized this politi- cal polarization of law. Tyson asks, “What happens in the courtroom? It doesn’t go to what’s right, it goes to who argues best...and Congress is half that profession.” As Tyson notes, “the act of arguing, and not agreeing, seems to be fundamen- tal to that profession.” The law thus depends primarily on rhetoric, the idea that amidst a slew of opposing arguments the truth will somehow emerge.

This approach is quite opposed to the scientific method. Scientific findings are only deemed worthy with exacting protocol, rigorous testing, and and extensive peer reviews. And even then, publication invites criticism that spurs further research. Congress, however, is a body of 100 Senators and 435 Representatives. In the chambers of government, any opinion, no matter how vitriolic or uninformed, is given a platform. If we consider our ever-changing and technologi- cally sophisticated world, the United States can unquestion- ably benefit from the participation and example of more scientists in government, regardless of political affiliation.

In the creation of the Federal Reserve, Congress once acted to shield our monetary policy from the tyranny of political rhetoric and gain. It may be time to adapt the same model for scientific issues. Our policy still suffers from political equivocation in place of scientific truth, scientific illiteracy masquerading as insight. Yet it is not the outspoken blunders of Todd Akin and George Broun that endanger our national interests, but the quiet assent that allows our elected officials to disenfranchise the scientific enterprise in America. As Neil DeGrasse Tyson asserts, “Science is distrusted not because of what it can do, but because people don’t understand how it does what it can do.” Perhaps we can start with our elected officials.

<strong>JOHN AURELIO B’14</strong> is globally cool.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8277</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:18:50</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:18:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>science-and-the-state</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>When We Wander Onscreen As Ourselves </title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8281</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:33:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8281</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GethardJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8282" title="GethardJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GethardJPEG.jpg" alt="" width="438" height="504" /></a>

&nbsp;

by Emma Miller
<div>
<div>

Chris Gethard is a mainstay at the Upright Citizens Brigade Theatre in New York. His anti-talk show, The Chris Gethard Show, began on the UCBT stage in 2009 and moved to Manhattan Public Access in 2011. While the theme of each episode changes drastically from week to week, a typical show will involve viewer call-ins, tazing, and some sort of emotional catharsis. We talked about positivity, failure, and the Cult of Gethard.

<strong><em>The College Hill Independent</em></strong>: You’re from an improv back- ground—how has working with UCB people on The Chris Gethard Show informed your decision not to plan the end of each show?

<strong>Chris Gethard</strong>: Even though the public access show is an hour, the most planned shows are still only about 75 percent, and those are the ones that we really sit down beforehand and know the most about what’s going to happen. Because every- body is from an improv background—the people on camera, the people in the control room, the writers of the show—I think we all feel that it works best for us not to be locked down. One of the things we’ve discovered with our show is that callers can call up and affect things so much, the micro- phones can break because the studio’s unreliable, but pretty early on we realized those things were some of the best mo- ments. The unexpected stuff plays to our history and strengths as improvisers. Setting a goal of “A, B, and C will happen” and then A, B, and C happens is a very good thing, but I think it’s more interesting and risky and ultimately funnier if it’s A, B, and C will happen and the D, E, and F we’ll figure out along the way. To me, that’s the next step; I don’t know what’s going to happen, but I think that’s part of what the audience likes.

<strong>Indy</strong>: The audience has a lot of power on the show and rep- resents a larger following that’s become a real community— what role do you play in that cult?

<strong>CG</strong>: Well, I feel like I’m sort of a curator of that community. The Gethard Show evolved from its earliest intention of mak- ing it a parody of a late night talk show at the UCB Theatre, and it quickly turned into something else at UCB. Public Ac- cess has changed that more and more. You know it’s a comedy show, but it’s also a strange art project in its own right. I think a lot of that is the community that we’ve built up via the In- ternet, and I do feel like it’s my job to challenge that commu- nity and to curate it, and to set the tone of what it is through helping find its interactions that I think are positive and lead to humor and creativity. I really like it. I really like designing shows that use the community as well. They are obsessive. One of my favorite shows was where audience members could submit characters for the show, and we were going to try to find new recurring characters that were fictional because we didn’t have enough of them. We invited people to submit names of characters, but they couldn’t describe anything about them. We were getting all these names and then our writers took those names and came up with basic premises, then gave those basic premises to different improvisers of New York. The basic premises we gave to actors who were improvisers and they filled out the rest, and by the end of the show you could be a kid in Ohio who turned in some random name, and you might see what happens when it shows up on your computer screen later that week. To me, that’s a pretty amazing thing that we get to do now, and I don’t think enough people are doing stuff like that. I’m glad to be one of the early experimenters with it, but none of it would work if we didn’t have a community that cared about the show and what it is.

</div>
<div>

<strong>Indy</strong>: I think that because of your role in the show, it is easy for people to think you are the persona you play on the show. What is the line between you, Chris Gethard, and Chris Gethard as curator and host?

<strong>CG</strong>: That’s a really good question and a very astute thing that a lot of people don’t realize, which is that I’m Chris Gethard and I host the show, but on the show all those characters have amplified aspects. Shannon comes off as this tough, intimidat- ing person, and she has that side to her, but she’s also a really sweet person. It’s just the show’s medium bringing that to the surface hard core. Murf comes off as this badass wild man, and he has that side to him, but he’s also a really loving guy in a committed relationship who also loves his friends. I think that the characters on the show are us, and I’m that guy that you see, but I have a more well-rounded life than the show presents. That’s an hour of my week with the camera pointed me and an adrenaline rush in a specific environment. It’s a very interesting thing in how people read my book and sense that I’m an honest person, and I am, in my work, but it’s still not my whole life. I remember I actually once got in a fight with my brother where I said something on the show that was nasty to a caller because the caller said something nasty to Shannon and I went off on the guy. My brother was like, “You’ve gotta be careful, man, because you’re supposed to be the nicest comedian in the world,” and I was like, “Well, I’m not that, I’m not.” I mean, maybe in certain instances I’ve been seen that way, and that’s a very nice thing and I’m glad I’m a nice enough person to get that going. But, I’m also the dude where if you mess with my friends, I’m gonna yell at you. If you say something mean to someone I care about, I’m gonna go back at you. I think that was an instance where a part of my life that usually doesn’t show up on TV showed up on screen and was kind of jarring to my own brother. Yeah, it’s a very strange line we walk being that we wander on screen as ourselves, but those are characters. Those are people who have 23 other hours in their day and six more days in their week. The hour you see them on the show, as much as we do connect with our fans, is still entertainment. It’s still comedy, and it’s been very trippy to deal with that and see how it turns out.

</div>
<div>

<strong>Indy</strong>: How would you define your relationship to positivity? “Loser is the new nerd” is kind of the mantra of the show, but does that mean being positive about failures or being satisfied with no success?

<strong>CG</strong>: I think the whole thing started because a lot of people were wearing non-prescription glasses, and to me it’s funny that all of a sudden you can wear a sweater and a bowtie and that’s a very hip thing. You’re in a certain class of kid if you’re left thinking, “Well, now what do I have,” and so I call myself a loser and encourage other people who feel like losers to feel okay with it. One of the things that I always say to people when I teach improv and respond to people who ask for comedy advice is that you have to get good at failing. Failure is very much a skill, and I think the whole idea of “loser is the new nerd” extends that to life in general, rather than limiting it to artistic pursuits. I think a lot of people have connected with that idea because it allows you to stop apologizing for being someone who fucks up and doesn’t necessarily have positive moments all the time. I think you can release a lot of pressure in your life if you do sort of say that it’s not easy for anybody. You asked what my relationship to positivity is, and at this point in my life I’m a pretty positive person, but there’s a real chip on my shoulder about getting there. There’s been a lot of anger in my early life that led me to being a very positive person. I had to fight through a lot of negative stuff and a lot of anger and feelings of bitterness and managed to let that go, and I’ve become a pretty happy guy with a pretty good outlook on things. I think that whole side of the show is encouraging people younger than me to drop the negative side of it and just embrace it. Everything good that’s ever happened to me, every girl who’s ever liked me, every professional success I’ve had has been rooted in the things I used to be ashamed of. Everything bad has made me work harder to- wards bigger goals, and it was the flaws that wound up paying off. It was the things I used to want to hide about myself that became the things people embraced about me, and I think that’s a pretty positive thing to put out there.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8281</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:33:24</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:33:24</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>when-we-wander-onscreen-as-ourselves</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Mourning</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8285</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8285</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[by Robert Sandler
<div>

I’ve found bits of everyone in you. There is no more grass in my yard, only clover. Found a way through fields one day and fell. No one lifted me and I lay there heaving.

When foggy air brought a bat to my room I captured him naked. In the rain when Zampanò said “he cannot slaughter that tiny sliver of space,” the foxes were screaming. My grandfather cut my great grandmother down from the vaulted garage ceiling. My mother is sweeping onion skins off the counter. These narratives need complication, a string of beacons from rooftop to rooftop.

The morning complicates, half light for a half-wit. I am running across the vacant lots. The children next-door had a burial for their cat. Sabine, at six years old, wore all black. This was
the nerve of wandering or the recognition of a currant, pesticide over pitted skin, tongue to protection. Even in a reverie bound by strong cords, shadows serve as proper mirrors. Reflection as gain and lack, nuance in the feathered edges. Shadows change in color or surfaces change in the light. These are tell tale signs, swim with me forever, do not once rise for breath:

Expansions draw upon muscle memory; the swing set cast in shadow from the vantage of my room.

These are dangerous claims to make, any sort of infinite or positive. I speak of the future in a graspless fashion for fear of ever being right.

Sitting across from bare legs, the thumb crevassing your thighs flashed a penis.

I do not know how to feel precious things as my ligaments are mismatched armatures. A wooden dolls with tines for hands,
pinch - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - pinch.

We watched simplified gestures in the same room, rows apart. Thick sluttish legs, legs like cassiopeia, waiting for you. I am a vacant face in the corner my funny ginger nymphet. You live above a sandwich shop and overcook eggs. I am wary, walking in the rain has often driven this tight lipped feeling from me.

There is this ritual of grabbing which makes me feel used and feminine. I waggle for it, the almond butter, the plainness. You move my thighs when I watch pink yarn from the window. Porcelain nails against my skin. Filaments of cherubic chuckles (the clatter is symphonic in the morning light.) Tile to tile of ecstasy while I await to wash your patterned back, a morose likening of dew. “Marry me.”

I plucked a flower from your dearest friend. I did not mean to, my fingers are so rarely still, so rarely spare.

Bother is used indeterminately, flanking my sides with beaded cowlicks and a cobweb. It has snapped all desire from me. In fact, I ache in absolution.

Walls apart they chuckle, I am veiled in slight plum and tangent grays. Beseech me to wonder and I will cry—fain not.

I veiled myself in mop and you in rotary scrubber and we were terrifying.

I have yet to retreat from your cause, it would be too pleasant if I had to run. My shoulder could not bare to move me. A shudder to shift, blatantly tired, fatigue awash.

My mother took me here when I was so young. I did not know the difference between transitive’s and thought the pool a vibrant mirror.

When you entered space a loss created an anxiety.

The world is seldom of its own accord. It is small flower filtering.

Remember deeply, in certain, in backyard lore, the toothy one rules all.

If it is true we cannot die. In certain, the overlap of valleys deepens a depth.

Only this is the exact temperature as the host of other times.

Now the sounds are at my throat, slowly working their way towards and infinite signals and winds.

There is a lofty bean on your arm which I gave you. You took two vicodin and we drew permanent signs.

The sweet summer air of Baltimore is licking the mildew of your fishtank. Wax and bark have tattered edges in the sunlight.

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8285</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:35:26</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:35:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>mourning</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The End (an agenda)</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8291</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8291</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Alessandro De Francesco

Translated from the Italian by Belle Cushing

tell me how i could tell you

that in those days i wasn’t there

that the tape was turning in vain

and a bend was nesting

under the covers

&nbsp;

we brandished the telephone   remember

we stopped looking

&nbsp;
<div>

at each activation of word in the darkness

i see a portion of the river in motion

illuminated by the signs and streetlamps

makes little twisters

flows in all directions

&nbsp;

somewhere else i was stretched out on the ground

emitting incomprehensible wails

&nbsp;

after she left i took the elevator

it banged gently against the sides

kept going down even

after the 0 floor blinked

&nbsp;

i wonder if it had kept going

what would have happened    would i

maybe have rediscovered

the toy car

lost in another city

while i pushed back childhood into the grass

&nbsp;

consciousness will not be granted

we inject ourselves with sequence shots

shooting a film already been cut

in others’ bodies

cutting into a curdled emulsion

&nbsp;

sometimes the pain appears

as an illegible presence        a bottomless surface

&nbsp;
<div>
<div>
<div>

at this point i would be framed

</div>
</div>
<div>
<div>

from above        standing before you

in the half-light

alone

in cross-section

behind the shutters in the grass alone

standing before you

&nbsp;

you were observed by a form

in the window of the building opposite

it was a bag atop a wardrobe

that to us was the face of a woman

&nbsp;

lying in the dark       in the bed of another city

i saw on the backs of my eyelids

a neck stretched out of proportion

and on top an alien face with no expression

&nbsp;

in the glass table

i watch the clouds

reflected upside down

city skies

still glow even at night

&nbsp;

but in a non-euclidean geometry         in a curvilinear space

you would and would not be here with me our hands would meet

in a room without eyes        the words

would appear framed in a close up

to tell us finally with clarity

when we got lost

&nbsp;

every concept was shaken like a tree

in the dark there were openings

in the summer

everything was red everything calm

&nbsp;

our film would be titled

on going home

it would be unraveled on infinite planes

and as leading actors

departure zones

a lampshade its plug stuck in the grass

and the letters of my name

written on the pages of your agenda

&nbsp;

but at one single sentence

look i have to go to know i am real

things became distanced

the pear’s porous skin         (and so it had to be)

did not hold

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;
<div></div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8291</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:47:55</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:47:55</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-end-an-agenda</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>(Some) Figures of the Animal at Home</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8295</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8295</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[by Maggie Milner
<div>
<div>

Their names were the names of heroines from the stories my mother told me in bed. She read to me every night until I was thirteen—the year, not incidentally, of my first tongue kiss. Robert Louis Stevenson, Mother Goose, L.M. Montgom- ery, then Louisa May Alcott, Conan Doyle, Austen. The women were all Emilys or Roses or Elizabeths or Marys. Those became the names of my sisters.

My half-brother was en route to Northwestern the day they were christened. My dad drove with his first wife across the country in an old green van and left their son in Evanston. My mom’s son had already been in college three years, and I was an only child for the first time, alone with my mother and father in a five-room house in the middle of the woods, which is still the only home I have to return to. I don’t know what makes you feign a family for yourself: desperation or unspent love or just generative solitude. Whatever it is, I woke one day with sisters.

They were all different. Emily was my foil: bossy and demanding, we argued over stuffed bears and bowls of pastina. Sarah was shy and deferent. Mary mostly stayed down by the stream hunting fossil rocks and red efts and didn’t come to dinner much. Rosie was pretty and conniving. They were my disciples, my flock, a bunch of girls about my age with no authority over what I ate for breakfast or how gently I scratched on the ears of my cat. They were lost boys and I was Wendy, standing in for their mother in a fort made of treebark and pine boughs. They loved me.

It’s hard to remember, by now, the games we played by the beaver pond and in the closet that was my first bedroom. I have vivid memories of their deaths, though: Mary’s dive off an overpass, Sarah’s drowning in the swimming hole, Emily’s side impact collision with a horse trailer. In bed after a story, my mother asked me where they’d gone. “Rosie was murdered,” I said. “I don’t know who did it.”

*

Mickey showed up one day when i was three, looking through the window at us from a church pew my parents kept on the front porch. He was bright orange with tabby stripes that made an M-shape on his forehead, which my mother used to say stood for “Maggie,” and which meant he was mine. We let him in and put a plate of tuna on the floor. He stayed with us nine years.

It wasn’t the first time a cat had adopted us. Roy was a brown shorthair who appeared in the garage, which was so crowded with old bikes and bed-frames that a car couldn’t fit in it. He wove like smoke through the stepladders and sheets of drywall until we finally caught him and brought him in the house. He died a few days later by the couch.

There was Wendell who arrived in the backyard, and Mavis who my mother carried home from down the road. Wendell disappeared after a while, and Mavis was diagnosed with feline AIDS and put to sleep. But Mickey stayed happily on, with the sagging paunch that neuters get, the flattish face, the tendency to curl up

</div>
<div>

In the closet on the shoes. We still say he was the sweetest animal we ever knew. Days after he’d gone missing, when Bonnie Craig called to say she’d smelled something rot- ten on her morning walk, my parents wouldn’t let me go with them to see. My mother came back to the house alone to get me, and we walked back together to the place my father buried him. He’d been run over near an apple tree half a mile away.

Since then, my father’s parents have both died; my brothers have gotten married; one has a baby on the way. Still, I haven’t seen my father cry like that since, on his knees on the fresh earth, the shovel beside him, apple tree moving overhead.

*

This is nonfiction, meaning true, meaning not a dream. Though I guess dreams of flying change your sense of the sky when you wake. I’ve never dreamt of flying, only driving.

The month Grandpa David first moved into the nursing home, Jamie Lundecker knocked on our door. I was building a stable for my plastic ani- mals out of blocks on the living room rug. Young enough to still hide behind my mother’s legs when speaking to grownups, I was scared to follow Jamie alone across the road.

The Lundeckers had lived across the road since my parents bought the property in the ‘80s, and always interacted with my family purely perfuncto- rily. Madge and Jamie were the kind of fences-make-good-neighbors neigh- bors, formal and distant, whose old age had made them craggier, recalcitrant. When Jamie died, Madge sold the house, its orchards, footbridge, cemetery full of dead Waldorfs and Sissums. When new neighbors moved into the house, they found the lawn littered with empty cartridges, the barn cluttered with pails of lead paint and ammo, a family of polystyrene deer riddled by gunfire that Jamie had used for target practice. A picture of Kennedy with bullet-holes through his chest and face. A sooty circle where his forehead had been.

It must take something extraordinary to forge a memory at that age, a kind of novel knowledge that the mind takes hold of as a lesson. I remember it though: how he led me down the long driveway to his house, veering off before the barn into a field. The grass was high and sun-singed by late sum- mer, and I waded through it in the wake he left. Halfway in, he put his finger to his lips and pointed to a patch of flattened grass. The fawn was still wet, tremulous and fearful of wind. Fresh from its mother, it was folded the way it had been in the womb, legs buckled bonelessly beneath it, eyes still sealed. The doe, sensing us, was off in the woods. We watched it breathe for a while, then he took me home.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8295</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:50:15</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:50:15</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>some-figures-of-the-animal-at-home</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Forever on the Edge</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8299</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 22:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8299</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/PunkJPEG2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8303" title="PunkJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/PunkJPEG2-219x300.jpg" alt="" width="219" height="300" /></a>

by Megan Hauptman
<div>
<div>

“The last time i played a show, the audience was pornographic with cameras,” Ian MacKaye says, scowling out over the crowd assembled in front of him. “Let’s all put our devices away and try to just be present for this one.” A few audience members sheepishly lower iPhones; one man in front of me tucks a hefty DSLR behind his back, the zoom lens jutting out into the audience like another limb. Most audience members look amused at the request, but not surprised. MacKaye is well known for his cantankerous style.

Ian MacKaye is one half of The Evens; the other half is his wife, Amy Farina. Both are dressed unassumingly in jeans and solid dark t-shirts. MacKaye wears a slouchy black beanie, though he is now almost 51. The two are playing in the charter school’s pale green assembly room. MacKaye is the former frontman of Teen Idles, Minor Threat and Fugazi, famous DC hardcore bands. Farina is the former drummer for DC rock darlings Ted Leo and the Pharmacists. The two married and later formed The Evens, a minimalist duo of drums and guitar backing soft, almost mumbled vocals, and have released three albums together: The Evens (2005), Get Evens (2006), and in November of last year, The Odds.

Home for winter break, a bunch of friends and I are at The Evens’ fundraiser show for the Next Step Public Charter School in Washington, DC. It costs five dollars, which has been the going rate for any MacKaye show since Minor Threat first hit it big. The school, which serves mainly older immigrants trying to get a high school diploma while working, used to be the site of the Wilson Center, a hotbed of punk shows and radical activism in the ’80s. As the show fills with black-clad original punks, I start to feel like I’m peering into someone else’s high school reunion.

Ian Mackaye is a punk legend, even beyond DC But he’s remained in his hometown for his whole life, returning to this city after every tour. He has donated most of the proceeds from his albums and shows to local causes and non-profits. His bands sang about homelessness and police violence, and the money they made from recordings went to shelters and public health clinics in D.C.

MacKaye began as the frontman for the Teen Idles during high school, a band that has been labelled one of the first DC hardcore bands. After high school, the Teen Idles disbanded and he and several friends started a new band, Minor Threat. It was the early ’80s, and DC was experiencing the AIDs crisis and had just been introduced to crack cocaine. MacKaye
had grown up the son of a newspaper editor, in the affluent Glover Park neighborhood on the northwest side of the city. DC was, and still is, one of the most racially and economically segregated cities in the country; the northwest is full of lush parks and independent bookstores, the southeast is a flat, treeless land where the blocks of row houses are often described as blighted.

</div>
<div>

Minor Threat only made it three years before disbanding in 1983; their most significant legacy was arguably the coining of “straight-edge,” the now-ubiquitous term for leading a drug, alcohol- (and often meat-) free life. In Minor Threat’s hit song, “Straight Edge,” MacKaye sang: “I’m a person just like you/ but I’ve got better things to do/ than sit around and fuck my head.” The song, based in MacKaye’s personal philosophy of sober living (defined as abstaining from alcohol, drugs, and casual sex), spread a new punk ethos; straight edge was an attempt to broach the occasional nihilism of punk music and connect it with a radical politics that called for active personal and systemic change. Straight edge has persisted as a punk subculture ever since.

MacKaye went on to form Fugazi in 1987, a much more musically coherent band with the same punk ethos. Shows were still only five dollars, and all the money raised went
to the causes MacKaye and bandmates were singing about. The band members were older, and so was their audience. MacKaye was no longer screaming about staying straight to high schoolers; he and his band crafted measured but still chaotic tirades about the state of the city. In “Cashout” (2001), MacKaye sings about corruption and eminent domain: “It’s official/ development wants this neighborhood /gone so the city just wants the same/ talking about process and dismissal/forced removal of the people on the corner.”

Fugazi hit it big, but they never left Dischord Records. Until they disbanded in 2003, they continued playing cheap shows in small venues in DC and all over the world, always donating the majority of their proceeds. They wouldn’t allow audience members to mosh or slam dance because aggressive dancing often hurt women and younger audience members. They mainly played in all-ages venues, and didn’t sell albums or merchandise at their shows to avoid commercialization of their music.

In 2001, just before Fugazi broke up, MacKaye and Farina formed The Evens. After playing in huge venues with Fugazi, some of which relied heavily on alcohol sales to furnish profit, MacKaye was interested in splitting off from any reliance on the commercial music scene. MacKaye and Farina dealt with this by keeping their set almost acoustic, which lowered their production costs and made it so that they could play anywhere with little equipment.

The anachronism of a camera-less show is kind of exciting, kind of uncomfortable, when I realize how much time I spend documenting my daily existence and then disseminating it via social media. For my generation, attending a show without being able to digitally capture a memento might almost defeat the purpose of being there, but as I look around I realize that my five friends and I are the only people of our age present. Most attendees look to be in their forties or fifties, save for the gaggle of under-ten year olds on the stage, assumedly the children of older attendees.

</div>
<div>

The stage looks almost like a living room, with a small rug under the drum set and two floor lamps framing MacKaye and Farina, though I have no photographs to remind me of the exact set-up. A red DC hardcore flag has been pinned up on the wall behind the duo; the triple stars of the district’s official banner replaced with the straight-edge triple X.

On one side of the stage, a group of eclectically-dressed children has gathered, some wiggling around to the music, others still and focused intently on the band as the play. One boy has closed his eyes as he mouths along with the words. All of the kids are wearing lavishly large and brightly colored protective headphones, a sure sign of their parents’ punk- rock status. I assume one is Carmine Francis, MacKaye and Farina’s four-year-old son, but I’m not sure which, because all of the kids seem to be intimately familiar with the lyrics to the songs. Some jam out on complex air-guitars; at the end of each song a few boys yell out requests.

Their favorite seems to be “Wanted Criminals,” a song about the police and private prison industry; the admittedly catchy chorus repeats “jails in search of criminals” over a furious guitar riff. MacKaye plays the song at the request of the cheering children; but not before prefacing it with a lengthy pontification on the role of the police in DC. A few minutes into his thoughts, he pauses and looks out at the audience. “I promise I don’t think about the police all the time.” Farina cocks her eyebrows and chuckles, “That is just not true.”

It’s hard to imagine, looking at Arlington, VA, now, that in 1981, MacKaye’s record label, Dischord Records, moved their operations to a small bungalow home there because it was less expensive than renting space in the District. I grew up in Arlington, a fairly affluent and loudly liberal suburb just across the Potomac River from DC. The metro corridor of Arlington—the central urban areas of the city built up around the DC metro stops—is now replete with high-rise condos, shiny townhouses and upscale chain stores.

Dischord Records operated out of a small house only blocks away from this metro corridor for over twenty years; it was outfitted with a practice space, a design studio, and
a darkroom over the years, and temporarily housed many DC punks and passers-through. The house, still owned by MacKaye but out of use as Dischord’s base, is tucked behind unassuming suburban shrubbery only a few miles from the house where I grew up. Minor Threat played at least a  few shows in my high school’s cafeteria in the ’80s; Black Flag, another DC punk legend, played at our school’s prom sometime in that decade.
<div>
<div>

I started listening to MacKaye’s music in the eighth grade, when a boy I had a huge crush on made me a mix CD with some Fugazi songs on it. I rocked out to “Give Me the Core” with my dad while driving to school in the morning, trying to cultivate the appropriate punk-rockness to impress the object of my affection.

In high school, I fell into the burgeoning DC punk youth scene. In December of my freshman year, I went to Positive Youth Fest for the first time, a weekend of punk shows and DIY workshops at a space called the Warehouse Next Door. I never really figured out how to blend into the punk aesthetic, but I went to Positive Youth Fest every year of high school, and even helped to organize it my junior year. This iteration of DC punk was just as angry as their ’80s forebears, and many of them had embraced that generation’s straight-edge lifestyle, but the two scenes seemed be glancing at each other across some sort of generational chasm.

The DIY punk shows I attended were overwhelmingly young; the main point of overlap with the still extant punks of the ’80s was St. Stephen’s Church, an Episcopalian church and occasional show venue in Columbia Heights. St. Stephen’s, which was MacKaye’s family’s church in the seventies, serves as the unofficial headquarters for Positive Force DC, an activist collective headed mainly by a cadre of 80s punk rockers. Ian MacKaye had his fiftieth birthday party at the church in March of 2012. St. Stephen’s also has served as a venue for two Positive Youth Fests, as well as a variety of other shows populated mainly by the under-25 generation.

for an aspiring punk with a dislike for screaming and mosh- pits, The Evens, with their incisively political lyrics delivered in a pared-down style, played exactly the kind of music I wanted to embrace. They sang about DC politics, police brutality, gentrification, depression, apathy. The tried and true punk topics were now hushed and crooned, so soft you could miss the anger if you weren’t listening to the words.

Their newest album, The Odds, features their reliably melodic condemnations, mellow and raging all at once. The photograph on the album’s front cover shows an almost-silhouette of their son running toward the camera, foregrounded against the green, billowing shrubbery of what is probably the National Mall. The Capitol building looms in the background, a subtle reminder of the intrinsic geography in all of The Evens’ music. The album cover highlights the fact that these aging rockers are now, first and foremost, parents. But the content of the album reminds listeners that having a kid doesn’t make you forget about how fucked up things are; if anything, MacKaye and Farina now have even more of a stake in improving DC’s future.

</div>
<div>

In an interview with NPR in December, the interviewer asked MacKaye and Farina what it would mean for them to have a rebellious kid. Farina answered, “Well, he wanted to be a police officer for Halloween.”

MacKaye paused a little bit longer before answering. “I remember being in high school and being struck by, like, the rebels,” he said. “Like, the rebellious people were largely the people who were self-destructing. And it seemed, like, what a shame. That’s their only option in this culture, that you have to destroy yourself? And I thought, well, that’s just ridiculous. But, honestly, I haven’t really thought about—I mean, right now, like, what does our son have to do to rebel? He has to take 25 minutes to put his shoes on. That’s a form of rebellion that will drive you crazy, you know?”

Punk is still alive in DC, in a youth culture where new bands are constantly being formed and shows are being organized. But it also lives in the continued work of activists like Positive Force DC and musicians like MacKaye, who continue to produce challenging, political, pissed-off music even, as they become the parental authority to potential future punks.

</div>
<div>

<strong>MEGAN HAUPTMAN B’14.5</strong> was a police officer for Halloween.<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/PunkJPEG.jpg">
</a>

</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8299</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-13 22:56:30</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-13 22:56:30</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>forever-on-the-edge</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[8304]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Week in the Underworld</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8319</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 22:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8319</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/WiR8JPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8320" title="WiR8JPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/WiR8JPEG-300x278.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="278" /></a>by Barry Elkinton &amp; Simon Engler

<strong>CREEPY CRAWLIES</strong>
<div>

Bugs are crazy. My dad’s an entomologist so I can say this with some authority. Growing up my dad worked almost exclusively on the gypsy moth, which was cool, but spending hours every day with a famously virile species of invasive moth means that you become completely covered in their pheromones, which cannot be washed away and persist for years. So every spring during gypsy moth mating season, female moths would follow my dad around by the hundreds, landing on him and piling up in the back of his car. I thought this was normal but it was not. My dad was a gypsy moth sex god.

So, yeah, bugs work in mysterious ways. But there’s perhaps no greater entomological mystery than the North American cicada, which spends its entire life underground, only emerging once every 13 or 17 years depending on the brood. And get ready, because the cicadas are coming back this spring. After patiently feeding on roots since their conception in 1996, billions of so-called Brood II cicadas—one of the largest North American broods, stretching from North Carolina to Connecticut—are expected to emerge from their underground burrows in late April and early May. In some areas, including urban centers such as New York and Washington D.C., densities may even exceed one million per acre.

The whole point of this spectacle, of course, is sex. The deafening buzz of the cicada—which can exceed 100 dB—is the sound of the male courtship song. When a female likes a male’s tune, she clicks her wings to let him know she’s interested. After copulation, the female lays her eggs in the bark of a nearby tree. The rest, as they say, is history, and within a few weeks the entire brood dies as a new prime numbered cycle begins. According to entomologists, cicadas likely developed prime numbered emergence cycles as a way to prevent predators from synchronizing their population cycles to coincide with the cicada’s emergence. The fact that the numbers 13 and 17 only overlap every 221 years throws off predators by making it extremely rare for two broods to emerge in the same year.

Despite this incredible feat of evolution, cicadas have a bad reputation. Many people associate them with the evil locusts in the bible, though locusts are grasshoppers and cicadas are more like aphids. They do have scary red eyes and they are very loud but they will
not harm crops or bite children. Still, as we prepare for the coming invasion, there are a few things to keep in mind. You may want to avoid using power tools because female cicadas might mistake you for a male cicada and try and have sex with you. Harmless, but perhaps annoying. And don’t forget, cicadas are edible! Broiled, baked, or barbequed, they are an excellent source of protein, as my father would say. Apparently they taste like canned asparagus.—BE

<strong>STINK CAVE </strong>
<div>

Hell stinks, and there’s a swimming pool at the entrance.

At least, that’s what the ancient Romans thought. Last week, the ruins of the ceremonial gate to their hell—a noxious cave equipped with a bathing pool and religious buildings known as Plutonium—were unearthed by Italian archaeologists near the ruins of Hierapolis, an ancient city in present-day Turkey.

Earlier excavations at Hierapolis had yielded dozens of ruined structures. But when archaeologists dug deeper, retracing the route of an ancient spring back to its source, they found an opening in the earth—and right outside, the buried ruins of Plutonium.

Roman use of Plutonium dates to at least the first century AD, when Strabo, the Greek geographer, described the site in his Geographica. At that time, priests would offer animal sacrifices, and pilgrims would bathe in a constructed pool near the cave’s entrance. A small building nearby bore an inscription honoring the god of the underworld. The cause of the complex’s destruction, in the sixth century AD, is unclear—either it was torn down by Christians, destroyed by an earthquake, or both.

Alas, descending into the pit at Plutonium today won’t bring you any closer to the Horned One. There’s not much inside the cave—some stones, maybe, and the desiccated shells of ancient bugs that couldn’t find an exit. Hades is probably deeper down.

But what the site lacks in evil spirits, it makes up for in stench. Plutonium’s smell comes from the fumes that seep in from the back of the cavern. These underground vapors are hot, and they’re poisonous— so poisonous, in fact, that birds flocking to the entrance of the recently excavated site dropped dead out of the air. These deadly fumes, rich in carbon dioxide, convinced the Romans that here, near Hierapolis, lay the entrance to the underworld.

Plutonium was, naturally, a holy site, and in Roman times only the purest—only the chosen—could enter the cave itself. Obviously, that meant eunuchs. More specifically: the eunuchs of the fertility goddess Cybele. They had to hold their breath.

O men of Rome! Send not the corrupted into Plutonium! Let only the purest—the roundest and tubbiest—enter the Maw! —SPE

</div>
<strong>
</strong>

&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8319</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 22:42:20</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 22:42:20</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>week-in-the-underworld</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="week-in-review"><![CDATA[Week in Review]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Big Hunt</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8327</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 22:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8327</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GoldRushJPEG-.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8329" title="GoldRushJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GoldRushJPEG--300x249.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="249" /></a>

by Erica Schwiegershausen

Mortality is rough. In the throes of old age, rich men find themselves faced with a crippling paranoia: what if no one reads my memoir? One solution is to pay people, but this isa little crass. Better to include a map and hints to a treasure chest containing millions of dollars in gold coins and nuggets.
<div>

The Thrill of the Chase, a self-published memoir by Forrest Fenn, an 82-year-old art collector and gallery owner, which contains a poem with nine clues to the location of a hidden chest of gold and jewels, is currently sold out. Collected Works, an independent bookstore in Santa Fe that is the book’s exclusive retailer has more than 4,000 copies on back- order. “The phones are ringing off the hook,” said the store’s co-owner. The dozen copies available on Amazon range from $65 to $232.

After Fenn appeared on “The Today Show” last month, his website crashed from the heavy traffic of visitors reading his poem. Yet Fenn says he doesn’t expect anyone to find the trea- sure soon, and has told news sources it could take anywhere from 100 to 10,000 years. Indeed, the poem is cryptic. “If you’ve been wise and found the blaze, / Look quickly down, your quest to cease, / But tarry scant with marvel gaze, / Just take the chest and go in peace.”

His plan is to release subsequent clues each month on “The Today Show” for the foreseeable future. Last month, he re- vealed that the treasure is hidden more than 5,000 feet above sea level—and also informed one woman via email that it’s more than 300 miles west of Toledo. For those who assumed the treasure was hidden in the Rocky Mountains, these tips weren’t especially enlightening.

But Fenn says the real point is to encourage Americans to get outside more. “Get your kids out into the countryside, take them fishing and get them away from their little hand- held machines,” he said on “The Today Show.”

He believes he’s succeeded, and estimates that thousands of treasure hunters will set out in New Mexico this spring. He claims he’s received over 13,000 emails from treasure hunters, including 18 marriage proposals—a good tactic, since most believe Fenn’s net worth is significantly larger than his bounty, though he is currently married. Estimates of the treasure’s value vary from over $1 million (HuffPo) to nearly $3 million (Hemispheres Inflight Magazine).

The city is preparing for a big tourism boom. Many Santa Fe hotels now offer “Thrill of the Chase” packages which include an autographed copy of the now scarce book as well as a “scavenger hunt” (romantic? sexy?) There’s also a “Thrill of the Chase” signature cocktail: a light blend of rum, sweet ver- mouth and Amaretto di Saronno sprinkled with gold flakes; and a Forrest Fenn sandwich: pastrami with apple sauerkraut on marble rye (his favorite).
<div>
<div>

fenn loves antiquities, and his 36-inch alligator, Beowulf. He collects painted buffalo skins and Plains Indians medicine bonnets. In his study, he keeps a brandy bottle that Jackie Onassis left in his guest house and a pipe he claims belonged to Sitting Bull. His house has been raided by the FBI as part of an antiquities theft probe, and there has been speculation regarding his involvement with a large grave robbing case, though he claims the feds have subsequently dropped all charges against him.

In 1996, Fenn believed himself to be on his deathbed. He’d been diagnosed with kidney cancer and told there was a 20 percent chance he would live. His friend Ralph Lauren was visiting him, and, predictably, fell in love with Fenn’s Crow Indian Hat—covered in white ermine skins and carved antelope horns—and offered to buy it. When Fenn refused to sell it, claiming it was one of his favorites, Lauren apparently said, “Well, you can’t take it with you.”

</div>
<div>

Ralph’s harsh words inspired Fenn to think a little harder about his legacy. In fact, he had a rather radical change of heart, recently telling Hemipsheres that “anyone who dies with over $50 is a failure.” Reflecting, Fenn remembered how much he enjoyed hunting down Remingtons, Russels and O’Keeffes for his personal art collection, and decided there was only one way to pass on the thrill.

He bought an antique bronze chest and filled it with treasures: a jar of gold dust, gold coins, large and small gold nuggets, pre-Columbian gold animal figurines, and some jewelry, including a beloved bracelet of turquoise beads which was excavated from a Mesa Verde ruin in 1903, which Fenn won in a game of pool. At the bottom of the chest, in an olive jar, is an autobiography—apparently much more extensive than his memoir, and printed so small that the reader will need a magnifying glass.

Fenn’s original plan was to head to the desert with a a pocketful of sleeping pills and the treasure. “Sometime they’ll find my bones and the treasure, but my bio will be inside the box, so at least they’ll know who I was,” he told The Huffing- ton Post. Then, his cancer went into remission. He put off hiding the treasure until his 80th birthday, at which point, he said, “I just got tired of waiting.”
<div>

But it’s no walk in the park. Last month, a woman from Texas got lost during a storm in the mountains near Los Ala- mos while hunting. She was rescued the next day, and Fenn has posted caution notices on his web site and several blogs. “Flatlanders don’t realize how dangerous it can be,” he told the Associated Press.

Meanwhile, a treasure hunter caught digging under a descano—a marker that indicates where someone has died or had their ashes scattered—is facing charges for violating state preservation laws. Last week, Fenn sent an email to KOB- TV Eyewitness News speaking out against the charges. “It is beyond me why anyone would want to prosecute that man. If I were his judge, I would fine him 10 bucks and tell him not to do it again,” Fenn wrote. “What has happened to our basic senses?”

Authorities have also warned hunters that, depending on where the treasure is hidden, finders may not be keepers—if the treasure is on state or federal lands, it becomes public domain. Fenn has declined to reveal whether the treasure is buried or whether it is hidden on public lands, saying that would give too much away. When asked whether he had con- sidered land laws before hiding his chest, Fenn told the AP: “I’m staying out of those discussions, except to say that it may be fun to redefine some of the terms.”

Not a lot has been said regarding the possibility that this could all be a hoax. No doubt anticipating speculation, Fenn announced that he will receive no royalties from the book; all profits will go to cancer research. His friends have also been quick to vouch for his credibility.

“I have seen the treasure,” bestselling author Doug Preston (whose novel The Codex, about a notorious tomb raider and treasure hunter who buries himself and his treasure as a final challenge to his three sons is loosely based on Fenn) told the AP. “It’s real. And I can tell you that it is no longer in his vault...He is not a tricky, conspiratorial, slick or dishonest person at all.”

Besides, Preston said, “He is having way more than $1 mil- lion worth of fun with this.”

<strong>ERICA SCHWIEGERSHAUSEN B’13</strong> has three gold teeth.

</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8327</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 22:51:55</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 22:51:55</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-big-hunt</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>MFA’d to Get Paid</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8336</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 23:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8336</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ArtWorldJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8337" title="ArtWorldJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/ArtWorldJPEG-300x260.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="260" /></a>

by Elias Pitegoff
<div>

In October 2012, gerhard richter’s painting “Abstraktes Bild 809-4” sold for $34 million. The sale earned the painting the superlative “most expensive artwork by a living artist.” The painting’s price sparked controversy in the art world, namely the critique that its monetary value reflected something outside of its artistic quality or relevance. As Blake Gopnick points out in an article from The Daily Beast, “The giant Richter smear that sold on Friday [Abstraktes Bild 809- 4] came 30 years after the photo-based paintings that made him matter as an artist, and it could be mistaken for splashy décor.” If any of Richter’s works are worth $34 million, it should not have been this one. The collectors and their agents sitting in the Christie’s auction that day seemed to be bidding not on how much they valued the work in itself, but rather on the prestige of owning the “most expensive artwork by a living artist” status-symbol.

The “Abstraktes Bild 809-4” auction sale is the latest milestone in the artwork as investment paradigm. It typifies the extreme lengths to which the wealthy are willing to go to own valuable art. The net value of the global art market has more than doubled since 2003, according to TEFAF 2013 Art Market Report. The painting (and any commodifiable form of artwork) has reached new heights in its function as currency in a capitalist economy. Such economic growth is cause for a reevaluation of how the art market works, what type of work it promotes, and how it effects the creation of a new canon of artistic work.

Living artists like Jeff Koons and Gerhard Richter sell single works for tens of millions of dollars. As Roberta Smith of the New York Times shrewdly points out, “the recent in- flated art market has created the illusion that being an artist is a financially viable calling.” While a small percentage of artists like Koons and Richter demonstrate the increased potential for artistic fame and fortune, they do not indicate an increase in financial potential spread evenly across the art world. The reality is that art sales are highly concentrated in the high-end art market. As prominent New York private collector and financier, James R. Hedges IV, noted in the New York Times, “The art world feels like the private equity market of the ’80s and the hedge funds of the ’90s.”

As Dave Hickey, art-critic/academic/behemoth art au- thority, pointed out in an article in the Guardian, art-collec- tors care less and less about anything but the monetary value of a piece: “It used to be that if you [an art-collector] stood in front of a painting you didn’t understand, you’d have some obligation to guess... Now you wouldn’t look at it. You ask a consultant.” The result is an inversion in the sense of value that an artwork holds in the eyes of art collectors. Collectors want to invest in work that will do well in auction. Where art that can be sold was once seen as valuable because it was good, it is increasingly seen as good because it is valuable.
<div>
<div>

The financial growth of the art market has also contrib- uted to a boost in enrollment at art schools and graduate programs. In the same New York Times article, Roberta Smith claims that because art schools and MFA programs have “ex- panded to accommodate the rising number of art students...” “[they] are now thoroughly invested in keeping these numbers high.” Smith’s claim gets at one of the biggest problems with arts education today: academic art schools and MFA programs are predicated on a false pretense--that paying hundreds of thousands for art school is an economically fruitful invest- ment. Certainly there are some students who would attend art school regardless of whether they ever made back a cent of the tuition they (or their parents) paid, but instead of risking losing the enrollment, art schools have changed their curriculum to be more career-oriented. The professionalization of art schools alone is not necessarily problematic. People need a source of income—why not give “artistic” people the skills to find employment where they can apply some element of their artistic ability?

</div>
<div>

What minor league teams are to major league scouts, MFA programs are to art investors. Irving Sandler, 87-year-old New York art-authority and author of the influential book The Triumph of American Painting, is quoted in the Village Voice article “How Uptown Money Kills Downtown Art” as saying, “Collectors have had an insidious effect on young artists. They move into graduate schools and offer these kids ridiculous amounts of money. The result is that even art students focus on what sells and continue to produce that kind of work, rather than experiment, which is what they ought to do.” Irving makes the claim that art as investment diverts valuable artistic discourse in MFA programs. The art as investment paradigm turns MFA programs into a breeding grounds for artworks creatively stifled by the desires of investors.

Art school’s relationship to the consumer-market was highlighted when Dave Hickey made a public spectacle of abandoning the art world. “It’s nasty and stupid... I quit,” he wrote in the aforementioned piece in the Guardian last year. He pointed to the way art students seem more focused on self-promotion rather than artistic creation: “When I asked students at Yale what they planned to do, they all say move to Brooklyn – not make the greatest art ever.”

One institution attempting to fill the void left by pre-pro- fessional art programs is the Bruce High Quality Foundation University. The Bruce High Quality Foundation University is the pedagogical vision operated by the Bruce High Quality Foundation (BHQF), a Brooklyn-based art collective. The BHQF is a (semi-) anonymous group, composed of five to eight members, most of whom are Cooper Union graduates. Its mission, according to its website, is to “invest the experi- ence of public space with wonder, to resurrect art history from the bowels of despair, and to impregnate the institutions of art with the joy of man’s desiring.”
<div>
<div>

Since 2004, the group has used satirical antics to react to over-hyped art spectacles and conventions of the New York City art scene. For example, the Bruces (as they are commonly referred to), pulled a miniature replica of one of Christo’s vinyl orange “gates” (a public sculpture on display in Central Park in 2005) around New York’s waterways in a small motor boat. The display, which they called “The Gate: Not the Idea of the Thing but the Thing Itself,” was an explicit reaction to and diminutive recapitulation of the Christo public sculpture and Robert Smithson’s 2005 “Floating Island”— a posthu- mously realized piece, in which a barge pulled a miniature replica of Central Park around the island of Manhattan. The Bruces’ piece reduced both the size and cost of the other two works. Moreover, by remaining anonymous the Bruces reduced the media’s capacity to make them into recognizable celebrities like Christo and Smithson. The BHQF website explains, “The foundation members were somewhat stunned by the attention that the project received. In large part the attention came simply because of a photograph taken by one man in the twenty-somethingth floor of an office building in DuMBo, and the image took on a life of its own.” The Bruces make a clear effort to direct the public’s attention to the way the media effects art spectacle. Their piece offered its audience a comment on the public’s need to generate media spectacle out of art spectacle. Their anonymity is a calculated hindrance—meant both to block the celebrity-making mechanisms of the media and also to draw our attention to that mechanism.

</div>
<div>

In addition to their satirical public spectacles, the Bruces have taken on the task of running an alternative pedagogical art institution. Since 2009, the Bruces have lead the Bruce High Quality Foundation University—“ a learning experi- ment where artists work together to manifest creative, produc- tive, resistant, useless, and demanding interactions between art and the world» according to their website. The BHQFU is, in part, an attempt to separate arts education from practices that cater to the pecuniary interests (i.e. catering to investors, professionalizing art curriculum). They are obstinate in their intention not to allow money or celebrity to divert discourse about artworks. Their stance: just because artworks can be evaluated based on their monetary value does not mean that they are inseparable from their significance as potentially lucrative commodities. As one Bruce told the <em>Independent</em>: “Artworks are also potentially useful as ironing boards, yet we seem to have no trouble rendering them separable from household utilities.”

In accordance with their non-monetary stance, all of their classes are offered free of charge. Classes are open to anyone willing to participate, meaning there are no pre-requi- sites. Further separating itself from the conventions of art aca- demia, the school’s curriculum is developed by the students. This DIY mentality has led to an eclectic course catalogue ranging from “Advanced Drawing” to “You Watching Me Googling You,” none of which explicitly cater to professional or career applicability. Their unconventional methods are not an attempt at, “reforming the higher education,” as one Bruce told the Independent, but rather “starting from scratch”. In creating a community of artists that fosters artist-led educa- tion initiatives outside of prestige-mongering art academia, the University appears to be safeguarded against the effects of cherry-picking art-investors.

Despite its lofty goals, the B.H.Q.F.U. is not completely immune to the need and consequent effects of art-investment. While the University aspires to be accessible to everyone re- gardless of his or her ability to pay, such a model is financially unsustainable. One way it has tried to cope with this financial quandary is by taking steps toward becoming a 501(c)(3) non- profit organization. Until this nonprofit status materializes, the university depends on the support it can find in the art world. This Spring the Bruces will host a fundraising dinner with high-end art collectors in the West Village. Practically speaking, the dinner makes complete sense: the school needs money. Art collectors have money. Its very existence depends on the funds of the art-collectors, whose influence on MFA programs it attempts to subvert. This tension was apparent in 2010, when the Bruces hosted the satirical “Brucennial” on the same night as the Whitney Biennial, which included a piece by the Bruce High Quality Foundation. The Brucen- nial demonstrates an apparent contradiction in their touted anonymity. The anonymity of each member veiled by the collective name “Bruce” has garnered a celebrity-status of its own. This paradox has left many critics skeptical. That there is a growing imperative for alternatives to expensive, academic art programs is widely accepted, but are the Bruces changing the art education system from within or performing that which they claim to satirize?

<strong>ELIAS PITEGOFF ’15</strong> has left many critics skeptical.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8336</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 23:01:23</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 23:01:23</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>mfa%e2%80%99d-to-get-paid</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="arts"><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>When I Get Back to my Body</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8346</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 23:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8346</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/BodyJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8347" title="BodyJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/BodyJPEG-217x300.jpg" alt="" width="217" height="300" /></a>

by Suzannah Weiss
<div>

The first time i left my body, I was fifteen. It was revelatory. For no particular reason, I looked in the mirror and was suddenly meeting someone for the first time. It inspired me, with my adolescent faux-profundity, to write a poem about the illusory nature of the self.

Then things got creepy. It went from spiritual revelation to identity fragmen- tation. I became more and more conscious of the split between the image and the self it represented. I would decide to move my hand and marvel that it moved in response to a mere thought. I wondered why my thoughts could control Suzy’s body and nobody else’s. I wondered how I even had access to Suzy’s thoughts. As I floated further and further away from Suzy, I felt invasive for even knowing she existed. I felt like a fraud for masquerading as her. I felt misunderstood for being seen as her. I hated her.

I feel the same sickening severance when I look at a picture and think, “Who’s that ugly girl in the front?” only to realize it’s me, when I hear my own recorded voice, and when I wonder why I see the world through my own eyes and nobody else’s. Maybe, you say, as if it’s obvious, because they’re my eyes. But they are mine only insofar as I see through them, only insofar as an optic nerve connects them to my brain—and what makes the brain mine? That’s a similarly disturbing problem. My brain is usually too tired to think about itself, but when it does, I feel like a snake eating its tail, so wound up it can’t escape its own belly, so thick from self-consumption that it chokes.

My childhood fantasies of the future always contained the hidden as- sumption that one day I would leave my body. Sometimes my future self was a Maybelline model with luscious lips and equally modelesque man-candy; later I envisioned myself as one of the giants of poststructuralist philosophy, sitting around a table with Derrida, Jacques Lacan, Foucault, and Barthes anachronisti- cally all at once. I did not become a supermodel, and I did not become a French man.

But as someone with two X-chromosomes, I developed a devalued and objectified body unfit for a philosopher. Looking for an exit route, I grew so airy and detached I felt my mind would expand like a balloon and float into space. Maybe it already had. I could be going about my daily routine without con- sciousness like a very advanced robot (I tend to believe consciousness is epiphe- nomenal rather than causally efficacious). For all I knew, I was already floating in space, connected via some wireless network to my body, perceiving its immediate surroundings only because I was collecting data from its sensory organs.
<div>
<div>

For a while i forgot i needed to eat, or perhaps convinced myself I didn’t need to. My mind had no idea what my body wanted. This was fine with me. I did not want to associate myself with something as base and material as food. My body was too heavy to express my inner ethereality. This asceticism bears similarities to anorexia mirabilis, a condition different from, but debatably a precursor to, anorexia nervosa, which afflicted several medieval holy women. Saint Margaret of Cortona, who died of starvation in 1297, wrote, “I have no intention of making peace between my body and my soul...allow me to tame my body by not altering my diet; I will not stop for the rest of my life, until there is no more life left.”

Saint Catherine of Siena claimed that she did not need food because she ate at the Banquet of God; she was above embodied existence. She renounced all carnal pleasures and had visions of marrying Jesus with a ring made of his fore- skin, which some might say resulted from sexual repression, just as some might say her mystical visions were starvation-induced hallucinations. But what I find more interesting is the possibility that it worked the other way around: she didn’t want food or sex because whatever satisfaction she could get from them paled in comparison to the fulfillment she got from her spiritual life.

Joan Brumberg argues that these saints were different from modern anorexics because they starved for spiritual, not bodily, purposes. Joan Brumberg has obviously never been anorexic. She writes that anorexia nervosa is a “secular addiction” in pursuit of “an external body configuration rather than an internal spiritual state.” But we are too closely descended from the likes of St. Catherine to have a “secular” addiction, and sometimes external configurations gain their power from the internal states they symbolize.

</div>
<div>

The main difference I see is that the out-of-body experiences of St. Cath- erine consisted of self-discovery (if also insanity), whereas I discovered a non-self. Rather than saying “this is what I am—an ethereal soul!” my mind had no iden- tity and thus could attach itself to anyone or anything, a parasite surviving off its host. I think of Voldemort on the back of Professor Quirrell’s head, feeding off his body until he gained the power to grow a body of his own. Perhaps my image of myself as a male poststructuralist philosopher resulted from this belief that my mind would eventually sprout a body to better fit its self-conception. But could a mind without an identity physically express itself? Maybe not. Still, I could not help but think that maybe if I lived in a body less fraught, less determinative of how people think of me—in other words, less female—the task might become possible.

One account of disembodiment that sounds more akin to my experience came from Marya Hornbacher’s Wasted: A Memory of Anorexia and Bulimia: “I suddenly felt a split in my brain: I didn’t recognize her. I divided into two: the self in my head and the girl in the mirror. It was a strange, not unpleasant feeling of disorientation, disassociation. I began to return to the mirror often, to see if I could get that feeling back. If I sat very still and thought: Not me not me not me over and over, I could retrieve the feeling of being two girls, staring at each other through the glass of the mirror. I didn’t know then that I would eventually have that feeling all the time. Ego and image. Body and brain.”

Like Hornbacher’s, my mind-body splitting was the precursor to an eating disorder, a self that took up residence in my mind when I was fifteen. Carolyn Costin, a psychotherapist specializing in eating disorders, articulates this phenomenon: “Eating disorder symptoms are the behavioral component of a separate, split-off self, or what I have come to call the ‘eating disorder self.’ This self has a special set of needs, behaviors, feelings, and perceptions, all of which are dissociated from the individual’s core or what I call ‘healthy self.’” I (the observer, the mind, the eating disorder self ) stifled and silenced the other voice, “my” own, until I (the observed, the body, the healthy self) became a mere body used to fulfill my sadistic desires, or perhaps masochistic ones; it is hard for someone split in two to tell the difference. But I don’t think this sadomasochist was the only voice in me, or else its pleasures would have been fulfilled and it/I would have been happy. I imagine another voice calling out to me as I walked through the halls of my high school, a voice within my gut that grew softer as I floated away and away from “my” body.
<div>

Unlike my initial mirror split, this episode didn’t feel like a mystical revela- tion. It felt like the crippling self-consciousness and self-objectification characteristic of this condition. I am not just talking about the condition of disordered eating; I am talking about the condition of being a woman. I am talking about internalizing an outsider’s image of my body until my face feels like a mask—all decoration, no sensation. I am talking about sensing that I can’t occupy the word “I” and thus becoming “you” to myself.

When I say “I,” I’m not sure whose words I’m using or who I’m referring to, but I’m sure that the speaker and the object of speech are not the same, and the words that define me are not my own. I cannot speak without splitting. Each “I” is a line drawn between me and the self I speak of. Each eye stares back at the other. Each act of speech masks me with another face, and through this mask I look down on my body in scorn, or at best alienation.
<div>
<div>

“Given the coupling of mind with maleness and the body with femaleness and given philosophy’s own self-understanding as a conceptual enterprise, it follows that women and femininity are problematized as knowing philosophical subjects and as knowable epistemic subjects,” Elizabeth Grosz writes. Women are defined by materiality, men by mindedness. This is to say not that women are earthly, but that Earth has been made womanly; it is not to say that men are Godly but that God has been made male. So many things have been imbued with references to men and women that we can’t speak of everyday concepts— presence and lack, hardness and softness, ether and earth—without speaking of gender. Man created God in his own image, and God created the world. It fol- lows from this syllogism that man created the world in his own image.

Just as St. Catherine of Siena configured her soul as a transcendent sub- stance trapped in the confines of Mother Earth and by extension in her body, I am a masculine-coded mind trapped in feminine matter/mother (both from the Latin root mater). I have chided myself for behaving as if the Cartesian illusion of mind-body separation is more than an illusion. I should know better, I think; I’ve spent four years studying the neural mechanisms of all thoughts and emotions, the embodiment of cognition, the situatedness of knowledge, and basically how Descartes screwed us all over because the mind-body duality makes no sense. Yet while I know this separation is merely symbolic, I can’t think away my own expe- rience, an experience driven by symbolic distinctions: mind vs. matter, male vs. female. Our culture’s conflict between mind and body is also raging inside me.

In Lacanian psychoanalysis, entry into language requires an extra step for women: the adoption of a male perspective, a perspective outside her own body, looking at her own head through eyes foreign yet all too familiar to her. To ac- complish this, language relegates her to the object of an action, or at best she is written as a subject in the passive voice. It is said that women are more empathetic, and that women spend more time considering what men think than vice versa, that women have more understanding of the male mind than men do of the female mind. That is because our culture has no concept of a female mind. If there is one, I leave it on the ground every time I float outside my body to think about it. Lacan famously stated that—<em>le femme n’existe pas</em>—there is no such thing as a woman. I believe I am a woman until I catch myself uttering such a statement, and once again, the “I” who steps outside my head, sizes me up, and classifies me as a woman with impossible certainty is not the “I” who is a woman.

</div>
<div>

The only way to remain sane has been to forget that the woman I observe and classify is, by most definitions, me. Disembodiment can be both your worst enemy and your best friend if you take it far enough. When I couldn’t bear the weight of the big fat pig I seemed to become in rehab, I told myself it was okay because my body is just a temporary vessel for an everlasting soul. When I felt defeated by the regrowth of curves I had resolved to remove since they first devel- oped, as if I had transformed from a human into a piece of meat, I made an extra effort to use the vocabulary of the male intellectuals I admired so that I could catch people off guard with discussions of postcolonial melancholia before they had the chance to peg me as a potential conquest. My mind is a magician, mak- ing the body invisible while chattering at the audience so they don’t notice it’s actually still there. This defense has proven productive for my education and may have even spawned the essay you are now reading—though my body’s having the last laugh now because this essay is from and about it.

The split is inevitable, necessary, even: without detaching from and ob- serving our bodies, we would not be self-aware. There are just more and less unhealthy ways to deal with the detachment. Freud contended that the world’s greatest artists became successful by channeling physical desires into intellectual pursuits. Like solid matter evaporating into weightless gas, this is called sublima- tion. Frued deemed it the only successful defense mechanism. My immediate re- action is to agree; I’m happy this way, I think. But which “I” is saying this? What would the other I say if she could speak? Where is she? Asleep until thinking-I wakes her with a kiss? Trapped in a cave with Antigone and all the other traitors of the male I?

Luce Irigaray claims that since language is fit only for a masculine subject, women must speak a different language to gain connection to their own bodies. But that can’t happen if there is no woman in the first place, and all that female empowerment talk about vaginas engulfing penises isn’t making me feel more embodied. So I’ve tried yoga, but every time I get down on the mat, I know it’s just a matter of time before I start sublimating. What comes down must go up. Everyone’s in downward dog and I’m in la-la land trying to solve the problem of induction. Any bit of mind left on the ground gets so engrossed in the move- ments that it merges with the body and loses consciousness.

Irigaray says that women defy language because they are so close to them- selves, and that one needs distance from something to speak of it. As I write, I approach the object of inquiry—myself—but I will never reach it. If I arrive at my destination, I will have to abandon it. By the time I reach myself, there will be no self to reach. There will be no “I;” I will be too close to speak. The sentence implodes, subject and object meld together, and the split disappears. I cannot speak without splitting into the self that speaks and the self that is spoken of. So I float off the page, and in the distance I see a girl with a face. It is a pretty face, but I take no pride in it; it is not mine. The most it is good for is to represent me so that I can float further and not be bothered. If I don’t become a Frenchman, I’ll get back to you when I get back to my body.

<strong>SUZANNAH WEISS B’13’</strong>s body is having the last laugh—this article is merely a receptacle for repressed libido.

&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8346</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 23:10:47</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 23:10:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>when-i-get-back-to-my-body</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="features"><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Moral Fiber </title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8356</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 23:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8356</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GrahamJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8357" title="GrahamJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/GrahamJPEG-300x176.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="176" /></a>

by Anna Rotman
<div>

Even though Ralph Waldo Emerson once called him “the prophet of bran bread and pumpkins,” Sylvester Graham was a serious man. A preacher by training and a lecturer by profession, he concerned himself with nothing less than the human condition. In his “Lecture to Young Men on Chastity,” published in Providence in 1834, Graham argued that people of all ages and of both sexes were causing themselves, and thus society, to become “debased, degraded, diseased and destroyed” by indulging in sensory excess of all kinds, but most significantly, in “self-pollution.”

A man chasing fame, he saw his Northampton, MA home one day becoming a museum in his honor. Were he alive today, though, Graham would likely not be impressed by his legacy. He became a household name, to be found in cupboards and pantries across America, but the graham crackers that we know bear little resemblance to the cure he developed for America’s most shameful ills. Indeed, the innocent s’more is a perversion of Graham’s enduring contribution to American childhood.
<div>
<div>

Graham developed “the science of human life” according to which self-pollution, lasciviousness, and, most acutely, masturbation, could cause almost every possible malady. He outlined his specific worries in On Chastity: it was not so much the “mere loss of semen” with which he concerned himself, but the “peculiar excitement, and the violence of the convulsive paroxysms, which produce the mischief.” He addressed his speech to young men, but was quick to point out that women were only by nature slightly less at risk than their male counterparts. He geared his teachings towards the younger generation because he had already written off the older perpetrators. The damage was too significant; the vice was too entrenched. Graham’s background as a minister and his readings in the new field of physiology heavily informed his work. Stephen Nissenbaum, in Sex, Diet, and Debility in Jacksonian America, explains: “Graham wished to purge the souls of his generation by cleansing their debauched bodies.”

Masturbation, and even excessive consensual intercourse, was a crime of the body and of the mind, and each one fed the other, leading the weakened victim down a spiral of physical and psychological impairment. His problems with this depraved sport were manifold. Besides the violence of the act, the effort that it required, and the exhaustion that ensued, there were three other issues at stake.

The first was the early age at which men, in particular, fell prey to the habit, a phenomenon that he saw as “one of the most alarming evils in our land.” Because of this, entire generations were reaching adulthood debilitated, “with a broken-down constitution, with a body full of disease, and with a mind in ruins.” The next was that the tyrannical occupation was a solitary one. The perpetrator did not need the consent of any other person and therefore the only prerequisite was an easy one: privacy. It seemed as though there was nothing stopping young people from indulging freely whenever they found themselves without company. The final and perhaps most threatening repercussion of self-pollution was the guilt that Graham claimed naturally ensued. This was the most insidious of problems: “every one who is guilty of it, feels an instinctive shame, and deep self- loathing, even in his secret solitude, after the unclean deed is done!” The depression that followed reckless masturbation posed a great threat to society: men were becoming listless, indecisive, and pessimistic. Today, this sounds like stale rhetoric, but Nissenbaum argues that Graham was the first writer to express “a new fear of human sexuality that would become one of the trademarks of the late nineteenth century.”

</div>
</div>
<div>
<div>

Graham was steadfastly ambitious and committed to curing this social disease. In an obituary printed in 1851 in The Farmer’s Cabinet, an Amherst, NH newspaper, the author describes the tireless lecturer: “His character evinced energy and decision, and his influence on the public mind was rather beneficial than deleterious.” The medical establishment was not so generous, however, and heavily criticized his theories. Perhaps this was because, like other health reformers, he was a proponent of preventive medicine and criticized mainstream doctors’ risky and ill-conceived procedures. He didn’t believe in carefully mixed antidotes or indiscriminate scalpel use. Instead, his prescription was for disciplined dieting and exercise.

Graham advised sufferers to stay away from strong foods—such as meat, alcohol, spices, and caffeine—for they would stimulate the organs too much. Furthermore, he encouraged regular exercise (except riding on horseback if it caused “involuntary emissions”), sleeping on a hard bed, and cold baths. In On Chastity, he taught his followers that all bodily systems were connected: “[E]very irritation and undue excitement of the brain and stomach and intestines, are calculated to continue the involuntary emissions; while the latter, in turn, keep up and increase the morbid irritability of those organs.” Furthermore, he considered the stomach “the grand central organ” that affected and was influenced by all the others.

As such, digestion was of the utmost importance, and anything stalling it would harm to individual physical and mental health, as well as the entire society’s hopes for a better future. Thus, Graham waged his greatest battle against white bread. Bread was changing quickly in the early 19th century, and he did not like the direction it was headed. In the growing market economy, bread production had left the household and Americans were suffering because of it. Graham reviled public bakeries, which produced multiple batches at once, relying on mechanization, processed flour, and additives. These breads lacked nutritional value and caused constipation, which Graham related directly to the urge for self-stimulation. “Farinaceous food, properly prepared, is incomparably the best alignment for such a sufferer...taken with or without a little good unfermented molasses, at proper times, and freely masticated, will digest easily and pleasantly, and will be sure to keep up a regular and healthy motion of the bowels.” It is for this exact purpose that Graham developed the recipe for graham bread, later to be transformed into a less perishable, drier cracker.

</div>
<div>

Nissenbaum explains that graham bread “was in fact nothing more than traditional homegrown and homemade whole wheat bread with a few added twist in preparation and an aggressively ideological rationale.” Social critics in the 1830s, including Graham, feared that the growing dependence on the unstable and anonymous marketplace was affecting American morals. This decade, then, saw the rise of prescriptive literature, informing eager young men and women on how best to run a household, bargain with shop clerks, and curb unseemly urges. Graham bread, however, was not fated to restore Americans to responsible self-subsistence. By the 1840s, bakeries were producing it en masse and historians speculate that entrepreneurial physicians were selling graham crackers as we know them as early as the 1860s.
<div>

Graham was a radical and was regarded with a mix of amusement and disdain, but that is not to say that a great number of Americans did not follow his recommendations for generations to come. James C. Whorton argues in his article “Patient, Heal Thyself: Popular Health Reform Movements as Unorthodox Medicine,” that he was the main voice of the health reform movement. It certainly helped that his home base was New England: Whorton describes Boston as the “smug center of reformist sentiment.” It was such a hotbed that angry Bostonian butchers who were threatened by Graham’s promotion of vegetarianism mobbed him on more than one occasion.

The illustrious reformer died at the age of 57. In his final months, he broke his own diet by eating meat and drinking alcohol in a last-ditch effort to cure himself. The physician who cared for him in his last year was unable to diagnose his illness, and, in an ironic twist, blamed it on the “somewhat irregular life” he had led.

</div>
<strong>ANNA ROTMAN B’14</strong> loves steak.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8356</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 23:20:54</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 23:20:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>moral-fiber</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="food"><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="metro"><![CDATA[Metro]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Close Enough</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8369</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 23:28:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8369</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[by Ellora Vilkin
<div>
<div>

An acting teacher once told me the most intimate thing you can do on stage is touch someone’s face. You could brush away an eyelash, maybe, or a funny strand of hair. Or cup an upturned chin with a finger or two. This isn’t obvious—to be intimate implies sex, and most plays and nearly all musicals contain at least an embrace, if not a kiss. But somehow, before an audience, hand-to-cheek reads more familiar than bare skin on skin, when one person reaches toward another’s face and no one swerves.

Touching someone’s face on stage or off means they trust you enough to let you reach toward six of the holes of their body—their wet eyes and mouth and dark seashell ears. It means they trust what you are enough to maybe let you in. But how often do we let the people who are not our mothers or fathers hold our faces in their hands?

Stephen Dunn writes that intimacy is the feeling of being ter- ribly understood. His poem “Connubial” describes the danger he felt when, he writes, “with alarming accuracy / she’d been identifying patterns I was unaware of—this tic, that / ten- dency, like the way I’ve mastered / the language of intimacy / in order to conceal how I felt—”

Terrible understanding then, the opposite of loneliness, when nothing can be hidden. Not the trifling sources of unease, not the names tucked into small prayers before sleep, not even the red velvet linings of eyelids. This is the price of closeness, of shared privacy. This is crushing familiarity. When you are known so wholly—consumed in the knowing—as to be used up and ready to discard.

//

This is my wrist in your hand, this is my body in quiet; this is your hand on my wrist, this is your body in situ.

This is my body in stitches. This is the shaking off, and the quaking of,
You and me splitting now, together
at the sides.

//

My mother says never to date actors, even though they are of- ten beautiful. And I have, twice, dated actors, but only briefly. I have, always, allowed myself to be stricken with peoples’ outsides.

Thing is, actors have studied how to put the moon in their eyes, to mirror others’ actions so as to make them comfort- able, to listen and repeat. They know that a touch on the upper arm is familiar, but not assuming, and that trailing the backs of their fingertips along the side of someone’s face will make their cheeks pink and ripe to touch.

From studying acting, my mother learned that it is easy to trust those with whom you step into another world. It is natural to look to fellow actors, to those with whom you have contracted to suspend reality, for comfort and company. It is telling the way that feigned intimacy creates connections that feel eerily real.

</div>
<div>

//

Al Berkman wrote in his 1961 Singers’ Glossary of Stage Jar- gon that “The Intimate Position of the head is that in which both the face and the eyes are directed squarely toward the other person.” Attachment, then, begins with the eyes.

//

1. Explain the procedure to the patient with his/her eyes open. For example, “I am going to touch various parts of your arms (or other body part) with this instrument. I will touch you with either one or two points, and you tell me if you feel one or two points when you feel the touch.”

2. The patient closes his/her eyes, or vision is otherwise impaired.

3. Apply light and equal pressure across the two points.

4. Have the patient identify if they feel one or two points.

5. Move the two points closer together across consecutive trials until the patient cannot distinguish the two points as separate. Document findings.

Note: This test is used to determine the level of enervation in a particular patch of skin; that is, how well a patient can tell two things apart. Eventually, when the two points of the instrument get close enough together, the patient will only be able to perceive a single point.

The tiniest bit of space between makes all the difference.

//

A voice soars in the soul, as gentle and expected as the soft rush of one’s own breath fogging a glass. No one can predict it coming, this feeling, yet its arrival has always felt to me as natural and irresistible as a shiver. It is certain nearness, of trusting enough to lean quivering hinged jaws into the moist flesh of a palm. To be deeply known and still kept: a tingle in the gut that echoes three inches beyond the body in all direc- tions.

//

By singing all of Fauré’s art songs for high voice, I establish a familiarity with his body of work. By kissing Paul four days a week for two months, I establish a familiarity with his body. The difference between intimacy with things and intimacy with people is synechdotal. I am not intimate with the com- poser himself, just his work, but because I am intimate with

</div>
<div>

Paul’s mouth, it is inferred that I am also intimate—close, dear, private—with him. His parts represent the whole. In that particular case I did care for the whole, though this has not always been true. I resent being handled gingerly by men with whom I have been intimate, who tend to assume I feel intimately toward them all of the time.

//

Cross-legged on the floor of my dorm room, I open and read his letter, his penciled words on looseleaf in shaky, schoolboy cursive and this is what I feel: one hundred tiny and precise and mechanical punctures on the soft underside of my jaw, along the v of my hips, during. The press of icy hands into soft flesh. The places he used to lay his lips. I read about how our sex became his guilt and how he had fasted and prayed and been forgiven, how he hoped I would be forgiven too.

It was a long time ago but he still breaks something that was whole and that I didn’t know I wanted kept that way. I mail it back to him with a three-by-five card reminding him that there was never a third person in bed. Don’t write me.

//

Joni says, Remember that time you told me, you said love was touching souls?

Part of you pours out of me in these lines from time to time, she says.

//

My father refused his bar mitzvah at 13, but he is the one who taught me to pray. In the soft voice kept for stories, he taught me to say, “Dear God, please bless...” and then list my loved ones, picturing their faces. He said praying was about loving, not going to church. He said that I could name whomever I wanted. But when I started loving outside my family, I wor- ried that the new names would know somehow that I had beamed their faces into the ether. I worried it would scare them away, that admission of care, the closeness of holding a face in the mind just before the quiet of sleep.

Standing before a roomful of people, I lean in toward a stranger. I am facing Johnny, picturing Paul, softening into the space between. If I do it right, the blue eyes turn brown and there’s a little lurch. And I hope it looks real, or at least close enough.

//

Look how his thumb skates along her jaw

Look how she stills

Look how the phase of her face shifts, waxing

Look at the space between them, waning

Look how his hand drops, fast and hot

Look how there is nothing left.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8369</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 23:28:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 23:28:27</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>close-enough</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="features"><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Threefoot Building</title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8374</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 23:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8374</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>

<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/3footJPEG.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8376" title="3footJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/3footJPEG-300x281.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="281" /></a>

THREEFOOT BUILDING was printed in gold block letters on the broken glass door. All around the door were colors and sea shapes in a pattern: orange waves, indigo flowers, pink shells. Rays of light, too. We looked up towards the building’s crown, where some copper was missing and some had gone green. Windows were boarded up on every story.

When my mom was young she stopped with her family at Wiki Wachee Springs, on the way from Long Island to Miami in a car. I’ve always known about the glass-bottomed boat there. She stood on the glass with her family and looked down at mermaids in the blue water. The mermaids wore sherbet swimsuits and breathed through long hoses while they danced.

Meridian was empty when we hopped out downtown, save for one lost man moving in slow circles around the municipal park. All the fonts on the old storefronts looked how I hoped they would. It wasn’t raining but the sky was grey, except for one space in the clouds where afternoon light was coming through. I ran back and forth across the main street, putting my arms around my slow- walking friends, running away again. We took pictures in front of the Art Deco courthouse and the vacant department store. We yelled to one another, performing, like we were on a set that belonged to us. It was strange how much taller the Threefoot Building was than anything else in Meridian. We couldn’t help but move towards it.

I was lying naked in the dark on the floor of my mother’s studio, which is almost completely white. She owns hundreds of colored objects, but even those are behind a white sliding wall. I had taken drugs and I was lying next to someone who scares me. I think she scares me because she wants to be an artist, but also because she is scary. She is Jewish, in the sense that she has a quality which I know my dad fell in love with when he was my age. I told her about the Threefoot Building, while her arms were around me. When I thought about it the next day it made me feel sick. She had a part of my mind, a real one, but I’d given it to her because I knew that she wanted it, and because I wanted her to have it, too.

I want to have a larger interest: in tall empty buildings, especially ones in small cities. My interest, then, lies in what happens when these buildings are empty. This project will consist of me going to small cities that I haven’t heard of and asking people how they feel about their big buildings being empty. I’ll only go to these places at the end of the day, when the light is how I like it.

The scary Jewish girl would like having sex on a higher story of the Threefoot Building. She wants to have sex in an empty building, in a place she’s never heard of, where the people seem only partly real. I know that this is part of what draws me to her. She would find an unlocked door, lead me by the hand up the stairs until she was ready to stop, and bring me to the middle of a room. I would want to be inside her, so much so that I’d already be thinking about it ending, but I would also wonder if there was someone in a nearby room—a kind, partly real person whom we were offending. She wouldn’t mind if the person heard, or even saw. She might like it. This is also part of what draws me to her.

The first place my mom photographed her friends underwater was in Robert Kitchen’s turquoise pool. He had just bought a mansion in Greenwich, because they were still young and suddenly he could. Her friends were naked, looking white in the blue with bubbles all around them. Later she threw dolls in the water, but first she went to Jamaica with Eliza, Peter, and my Dad, and wore a weighted belt in the ocean so she could see them swimming from below.

</div>
by Grace Dunham]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8374</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 23:37:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 23:37:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-threefoot-building</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="literary"><![CDATA[Literary]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Where the Frontier Ends </title>
		<link>http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8392</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 23:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/?p=8392</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/CompanyTownJPEG.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-8402" title="CompanyTownJPEG" src="http://students.brown.edu/College_Hill_Independent/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/CompanyTownJPEG-247x300.png" alt="" width="247" height="300" /></a>

by David Adler

The real work, the heavy lifting, starts where the frontier ends. The pioneers, the Lewis and Clarks, just drew their index fingers to the West and moved forward ho. Then, when it was all mapped and named, Neil Armstrong looked to the moon and said, upward. Even after that, we squirmed around, followed the empire’s imperative—out, go, spread. But today’s America doesn’t want to walk on the moon, and it doesn’t want a new war. Are we settled now? Is this it?
<div>

Mayor James Thompson of Sugar Land, Texas wants you to know that his city is not for sale. Which, at first, is not surprising at all, because usually towns are not for sale. This was in February, after SugarDaddie.com, a website that helps older men connect with younger women, offered four and a half million dollars to Sugar Land, Texas for the town to change its name to SugarDaddie.com, Texas.

“Really, it was never even a consideration of the mayor,” councilman Joe Zimmerman tells the Independent over the phone. “All of us in Sugar Land are very passionate and proud of our history.” In city hall, a plaque hangs on the wall, with pictures and little blurbs that tell the story of this sugar plantation town. Back in 1843, Samuel May Williams founded the Imperial Sugar company here, which has been headquartered in Sugar Land ever since. It was a company town—Imperial housed its workers, built schools for the children and hospitals for the sick. It was self-sufficient that way, and the railroads only helped Imperial to keep its little town happy and well fed.

The Imperial Sugar factory is no longer in service, now a big brick landmark off the highway. Still, Zimmerman notes, “we are very protective of our past, recognizing that we have moved well beyond a sugar town.” Asked if there were an offer to be made right here, right now that would persuade Sugar Land otherwise, he belts a hearty chuckle that rings through the phone. Names are names, and places are places, and especially in Texas, tradition is tradition. Geography, Joe announces, is not a commodity.
<div>
<div>

In 2005, the five members of the Santa, Idaho town commission vote unanimously to rename the town SecretSanta.com in exchange for at least $20,000 from the gift-sharing website. The company is allowed to erect signs all over town, though the town post office keeps its name so that there will be no disappointment when thousands of children, as do and have done for decades, send their annual letters to Santa’s Idaho address come December.

Five years earlier, after an offer of $110,000 and twenty new computers for the school computer lab, Halfway, Oregon becomes Half.com, America’s First Dot-Com City, according to the signs. Nothing, of course, is Dot-Com-y about it; Halfway is a small town along a main road, sitting in a vast, barren valley beside Oregon’s snowtips. Beautiful, to be sure, but a publicity ploy in name only. “We literally put the brand on the map,” Half.com vice president Mark Hughes announced.

The same year: Clark, Texas, a little town in Denton County with a population of just about 200, becomes DISH, Texas. EchoStar Communication Corporation offers the residents of DISH, Texas free cable for ten years; Mayor Bill Merritt is happy to oblige. “We really look at this as kind of a rebirth for our community.”

Topeka, Kansas becomes Google, Kansas on March 1, 2010 in a bid to help persuade Google to invest its fiber optic technology in the city. They held the name for a month as a push to attract Google’s “Fiber for Communities” program, which offered to install its new Internet technology in a handful of locations.
<div>
<div>

There is something irksome here, something laughable in the same way that Joe Zimmerman and the council of Sugar Land, TX laughed when they first encountered a bid from SugarDaddie.com. The idea of SugarDaddie.com, Texas first appalls us on a very immediate, superficial level. We would never want our children growing up in a hometown named after the venerable tradition of online dating. It’s quite similar to the feeling we get when we talk about White Settlement, Texas. A population of 16,000, the town needed to distinguish itself from the Native American settlement nearby. When city representatives announced a referendum to change its name in 2005, residents rejected the change by a landslide 2,388 votes to 219.

In this democratic assertion of White Settlement’s name, though, we open the door to a larger discomfort, one that transcends democracy entirely. Despite its questionable
racial politics, White Settlement stands for a tradition that its citizens are prepared to defend. In SugarDaddie.com, on the other hand, we are forced to confront a different kind of logic, one that seems peculiar largely because it is familiar: corporations target those facets of our lives thought to be off-limits. At the dinner table, my mother used to make us put our cell phones on the counter before we ate. If I texted under the table, I didn’t get dessert. When I visit my parents in 2013, we are texting each other under the table to discuss dad’s lamb chops, or checking our email, or doing something that we once thought to be not-dinner-table-appropriate. We grow accustomed to the technological tragedies of the past, the voice of the elderly scolding the kids these days waxes anachronistic, and we move to inhabit the new spaces that our companies carve out for us. An advertisement I encountered last month reads: “How to Tattoo a company’s Brand Name or Logo and how to Get Paid from Them.” Meanwhile, Google’s Glass project, a headset that integrates our in-the- world vision with our on-the-web one, seeks to refashion the living experience itself. We would, with Glass, wake up to Google, although most of us already do.

In this sense, the investment in geography appears to be the next step in corporate empire. First, the consumable, then the corporeal, now the country itself. The Corporate America—a formal, legal, explicit one, where public space is claimed as private, each little house on the prairie.com—is around the corner; that’s just the free market at work.

It’s a dystopic vision (and perhaps a paranoid one), the nation dominated by the Company Town. As Hardy Green writes in Company Town, “To those who like to think of the United States as a sweet land of liberty, the very words sound un-American.” If Americans are free, they cannot be bound to the corporation, who might, in this dystopic vision, administer where people live and what they eat and whom they worship.

“It’s true,” Green writes. “Company towns are un- American—and they are the essence of America.”

</div>
<div>

In 1903, milton hershey purchased 1,200 acres of barren land in Derry Church, Pennsylvania. He was moving away from New York City, where his candy shop had recently closed, looking to expand on his line of five-cent Hershey’s Milk Chocolate Bars.

He hired surveyors to map out the plot, and an architect to begin developing blueprints for his Hershey’s Chocolate factory and the town that would grow around it. “Such a place,” Hershey dreamed, “would serve as a standing advertisement for the Hershey Co., its wholesome values, and its products,” Green writes. There would be, in Hershey’s own words, “no poverty, no nuisances, no evil.”

And Hershey was right. His town had zoos and parks, schools and hospitals, pools and trolleys. Hershey workers received all of the benefits of the company town, with housing and medicine and retirement included. There was a junior college with free tuition; town churches received $20,000 endowments. Hershey’s wife Kitty developed the Hershey Industrial School inside the town, housing and educating orphans and providing them with $100 upon graduation. And, of course, there were no funeral homes or cemeteries allowed in the town; mortality and candy are unprofitable, albeit natural, bedfellows. Milton Hershey—who would act as the self-appointed mayor of his Pennsylvania Disneyland— was remaking the American city in chocolate. “The village had become such a sensation that little other marketing was needed—and the company ceased its print advertising,” Hardy writes.

</div>
</div>
<div>

Hershey, Pennsylvania would thrive in the following decades. Expanded production, new amenities, healthy hearth and home. Though different in style and scale, Hershey and the Dot-Com cities of our decade are based on the same mutual promise of exchange: big business offers services to town residents; residents offer control of their public space. Half.com offers a new computer lab to the school; Hershey offers a new school completely. This was how America was formed, industry first, people second, chasing each other westward across the continent.

George Pullman developed his own model town in the 1880s. In four years, he transformed 4,000 acres of Illinois swampland into a large-scale manufacturing town of 8,000 residents. In the city of Pullman, cable car factories loomed over an elegant residential neighborhood of tree-lined streets and brick homes with running water and functioning gas.

Green’s list is long: Firestone Park, Ohio of the Firestone Tire &amp; Rubber Company; Alcoa, Tennessee of the aluminum producer Alcoa; Kohler Village, Wisconsin of the Kohler Co. All the way through the ‘40s, when war-time production sprouted insta-cities throughout the West, and into the ‘60s. Valencia, California, for example, was planned by the Newhall Land and Farming Company, separated into little villages with landscaped boulevards that snake along schools and shopping malls and community centers and golf courses. “Built as Promised,” is Valencia’s catchphrase; “Awesometown,” its unofficial brand name.
<div>

The recognition of this history, though—of America as the land of the Big Business buy-and-build rather than the Lewis and Clark see-and-settle—is not an endorsement. Pullman’s Illinois model town famously erupted in labor unrest; Hershey’s, much later, the same way. All throughout the company towns of the early twentieth century—mining and coal, oil and steel—workers were exploited heavily by the company benefactor.

Yet the Company Town reminds us, against Joe Zimmerman’s hearty chuckle, that geography has always been a commodity in this country. After all, cities are incorporated, not founded. And states, too, were economic entities before they were patriotic ones. Hawaii, the 50th shining star, had sugar plantations; California, in 1850, had its gold. There’s a confusion in this county between what is public and what is private, what belongs to the country and what belongs to its citizens. There is something irksome about SugarDaddie.com, Texas, but perhaps it’s a discomfort with the origins of America rather than its future. Then again, maybe it’s both.

Still, Hershey was a real human, the type of flesh-and- blood human that, despite Citizens United and the new “corporate humanity,” we recognize as our own. More important, he was a human that lived in his little town in Pennsylvania. SugarDaddie.com has nothing to do with the cute, commercial town of Sugar Land, Texas in just the same way Half.com had nothing to do with the little green hamlet of Halfway, Oregon. This is the key difference between the history of the Company Town and its contemporary counterpart: one is named from within, and one from without. When someone gets on the Hershey’s Kiss ride at the Hershey amusement park, he is reminded of the real things that Hershey produced, the chocolate bars that were made in that now-defunct factory next door. SugarDaddie.com, Texas is instead a commemoration of a far-off organization producing something fundamentally immaterial. The production used to take place within the town; now the product is the town itself.
<div>
<div>

This reminds us: the jobs are not coming back. The real Company Towns of today’s American industry, or at least the bulk of them, are beyond our borders. But we would never see Nike, Indonesia or Levi Strauss, South Africa; these are not the places to which American companies want to direct our attention. SugarDaddie.com thus forces us to confront this new commercial America, one that has increasingly few monuments or landmarks to offer. The Company Town may have relied on exploitation, but it was exploitation that felt present within the community; it was the workers versus the boss, circumscribed by the town limits.

</div>
<div>

But capital is mobile, and labor is not. And so there is something about the Dot-Com ownership of America that feels far more in-the-shadows, pulling strings from an invisible skyscraper. These towns have no relationship with their owners, and there is no collective experience. That these websites are selecting cities with such similar names to their domains only serves to reinforce the perception of some sneaky sleight-of-hand. Who is SugarDaddie.com? At least we knew Hershey. He had a smile and a patch of grey hair on his head, and he liked to hold orphans in his arms in the photographs.

There is a part of the american southwest, a few hundred miles east of the Rockies, that looks like an endless checkerboard from above. Clean white lines mark off squares of maroon and brown flatland, each little parcel with its own terrestrial color. Big squares and small squares fit perfectly next to each other, and not an inch is missing from the patchwork. We’ve done an incredible thing making this quilt out of the continent; from the plane, it looks like it could never have been any other way.

It is a scary feeling to approach the geographical singularity, when all the villages on the Amazon have been purged, every nook and cranny of the ocean discovered and plotted and TED-talked. And it is because of the loss of the frontier, a fear that we can only build up now, not out. That isn’t to say that we are not expanding, filling out those empty lots on the outskirts of Phoenix or Las Vegas. But these are spaces that have already been named, even if those names are X35-F or Maricopa County-adjacent. They are merely awaiting investors.

At the end of the frontier, there is no more writing left to do, only re-writing. In the Dot-Com city, we find that the entire country is, in essence, becoming a derivation of itself. So while we may not like the original manuscript— White Settlement, TX, for example, or even Hershey, PA— we are even more concerned with the re-write, because we know who owns the pen.

</div>
</div>
<strong>DAVID ADLER B’14</strong> is the essence of America.

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

</div>
&nbsp;

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>8392</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2013-04-26 23:52:38</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2013-04-26 23:52:38</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>where-the-frontier-ends</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[8402]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
